Mother, I like her voice.
I want her to sing at my wedding.
She'll sing at your wedding.
I seek refuge in God
from the accursed devil.
"The Gulf's top female singer retires
under mysterious circumstances."
I called her many times,
but she won't talk to me.
"It's not just you.
She's refusing to talk to the press
or appearing in the media."
- People want to know the real reason.
- I'm leaving, okay?
People want to know the real reason
for this sudden retirement.
- Rumors have already spread.
- "Right."
I read the investigation reports,
but I want to hear the story from her.
Alright, I'll try to talk to one
of her in-laws. I know him well.
You must. She can pick the time
and place. I don't mind.
What matters is uncovering the mystery
behind her disappearance and retirement.
People are talking, not only in Kuwait,
but across the Gulf.
- "I'll see what I can do."
- Alright.
"My heart is always moved by
the sway of the gazelle's leader."
"When the gazelle sways,
it pulls my heart apart."
"My heart is always moved by
the sway of the gazelle's leader."
Peace and blessings be upon you.
- Beloved of God, Muhammad.
- "When the gazelle sways
it pulls my heart apart."
"My heart is always moved by
the sway of the gazelle's leader."
"My heart is always moved
- by the sway of the gazelle's leader."
- Peace and blessings be upon you.
Beloved of God, Muhammad.
"When the gazelle sways,
it pulls my heart apart."
"My heart is always moved by
the sway of the gazelle's leader."
"When the gazelle sways,
it pulls my heart apart."
"My heart is always moved by
the sway of the gazelle's leader."
Peace and blessings be upon you.
- Beloved of God, Muhammad.
- "My heart is always moved
by the sway of the gazelle's leader."
"My heart is always moved by
the sway of the gazelle's leader."
Well done, good job.
Well done, girls.
You've made us proud, Noura.
All the guests agree this is the most
beautiful wedding in the family.
Umm Abrar, we treat every wedding
as if it were our own
and the girls
as if they were our daughters.
And if Abrar wants me to sing
until morning, I'm ready.
That's no surprise
coming from you, my dear.
This is the payment,
for you and the girls.
- Thank you.
- And this is a gift from Abrar
from her dowry.
- I'm grateful, but I can't accept it.
- Really, Noura?
Do you want to upset the bride
on her wedding night?
Of course not.
May God reward you.
- God bless you, take care.
- You too. Bye.
In God's name, I look so beautiful
I fear I'll get evil eye.
There's not a single loose strand
of hair.
Because you made the hairdresser
burn your hair with the iron.
This is the result.
And what about your wig?
What do you mean a wig?
Seems like you're asking for it.
Enough! Take it easy, ladies.
You fight over every day.
I got the payment, girls.
Come on, one at a time.
- Move!
- One at a time.
Well, me first.
Hayat, it's not appropriate to find
a wife for your brother among the guests.
You noticed?
Was I that obvious?
Who hasn't noticed?
- Give me that.
- Everyone saw you.
And what's it to you?
- Say God's name, my dear.
- In God's name against your enemy.
What is this? My hands are sore from
playing the drum, and this is all I get?
Choose a wealthy wedding next time.
And how would I know if the caller
is rich or not?
You can tell from the names,
like Feryal, Dalia, or Lamia.
The modest brides
have names like ours.
Noura, Shams, and Marzouqa.
You're so funny.
Alright, next time I'll check
the guests' names before I accept.
Good.
Is your leg any better?
Neither medicine nor treatment helped,
but thank God, I can still walk.
Here, this is for you and your family.
- Where did this come from?
- Quiet, don't let Shams know.
May God reward you and protect your family.
I don't know how to repay your kindness.
Hadeel, here you go.
Good work.
That's enough.
Here.
Good job.
Noura, we're all going to have dinner
at Mona's. Won't you come with us?
No, my dear, enjoy.
My kids are home alone.
- Maybe next time.
- Okay.
Have a nice evening.
"He spoke to me with his eyes
And I answered"
"And I followed
That handsome, dark-skinned man"
"He spoke to me with his eyes
And I answered"
"And I followed
That handsome, dark-skinned man"
What are you doing?
We were singing, like you.
I became a singer
because it was all I could do.
If you want to be successful,
become a doctor, an engineer, or a teacher.
And you, become a lawyer, a pilot,
or an athlete, or anything.
But don't end up like me.
Come here.
Come here, both of you.
Look at me.
You have your whole lives
ahead of you.
And the world is full of opportunities.
Become whoever you want,
but don't end up like me.
Okay?
Come here.
"Journalist Mishal Zayed
Local News Section"
"The Gulf's top female singer retires
under mysterious circumstances."
- Hello?
- "Mishal."
"Noura agreed to meet you, but you have
to go to her house right now."
"Do you hear me?"
Give me the address.
"Okay, write it down..."
"In the name of Allah, the Merciful I
seek refuge in the Lord of humankind
the Sovereign of humankind,
the God of humankind
from the evil of the lurking whisperer who
whispers into the hearts of humankind
from among the jinn and humankind.
Allah has spoken the truth."
Peace be upon you. I'm Mishal,
a journalist from Al-Qabas newspaper.
I'm here to interview the artist Noura.
Have a seat,
my Mom will be here shortly.
Thank you.
I'm the journalist Mishal Zayed.
- I'm sorry if I disturbed you, but...
- Get to the point.
Okay. Regarding your retirement,
there have been stories and rumors.
I read the investigation report,
and it was full of ambiguity.
What ambiguity?
About why you retired.
You were the most
famous folk singer in the Gulf.
You even overshadowed top singers.
Are you ready to hear my story?
Yes.
If you insist on hearing the story,
the burden is yours to bear.
May I record?
Do as you wish, it doesn't matter.
Go ahead.
Five years ago...
I got a phone call.
Fawaz.
- Fawaz.
- Yes, Mom?
Answer the phone, sweetheart.
Okay.
Hello?
- Mom?
- Yes, my dear.
- A woman is asking for you.
- Who is she?
She didn't say her name.
- Hello.
- "Hello, Noura. How are you?"
I'm good. Who is this?
I'm Umm Murjana. You don't know me
but my daughter's wedding is tonight.
And she's insistent to have you
sing at her wedding.
It's an honor, Umm Murjana,
but I'm afraid I can't tonight.
It's the band's day off,
I won't be able to.
It's my fault, I should've called sooner
but I got too busy and forgot.
If my daughter finds out I forgot
to call you, she'll be heartbroken.
I'm sorry, I can't.
My kids are home alone.
But I can give you the number
of another singer who can be there.
My daughter won't accept
anyone but you singing at her wedding.
I'll pay you double your fee, or more.
Ask for whatever amount you want,
just come to the wedding.
Okay.
Noura. Noura!
- Say God's name.
- In God's name.
What's the matter? You look like
you're going to a funeral, not a wedding.
I hate that my kids are home alone
on my day off.
I thought you had something to do.
But why else do we work this hard?
We do it for them, don't we?
On another topic.
How about tomorrow we take our kids
to the amusement park and have some fun?
We always end up going on more rides
than they do.
Why not? We're still young,
beautiful, and full of life.
We didn't have stuff like that
back in the day.
That's true.
- Why is everyone so gloomy?
- May God protect us.
Come on, guys. What's wrong with you?
We're going to a wedding, cheer up.
Come on, "I met a handsome dark-skinned
man He signaled with his eyes"
"He spoke to me, I answered
And I followed him"
"I met a handsome dark-skinned man
He signaled with his eyes"
"He spoke to me, I answered
And I followed him"
Shams, this looks like the wedding
of a wealthy family that you wanted.
Yes.
- Shall we go in?
- Yes.
Come on.
Peace be upon you.
Marzouqa, what's wrong?
There are bones here.
In the name of God, the Most Merciful.
No one touch them. Hayat, please
cover them until we leave.
Good evening. I'm Umm Murjana,
the mother of the bride.
And these are my daughters,
Fayrouz and Zomoroda.
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Umm Murjana.
My daughters adore you,
and they came to greet you.
What an honor.
We like you too.
May we celebrate your weddings
as well, God willing.
How much time do you need to get ready?
Fifteen minutes at the most.
Take your time, I'll inform the guests.
Noura...
I have a bad feeling about this wedding.
Did you see their sharp features?
Even the blackness of their eyes
is frightening.
Yes, I agree.
As soon as they entered, the room
grew hot, the fire in the heaters flared.
Everything went back to normal
after they left.
What's wrong with you, guys?
Nothing is wrong.
You're just not used
to weddings of wealthy families.
But Noura, it's not just me.
What's wrong with you, Shams?
That's enough. Show me those smiles.
We'll talk after the wedding.
Smile, girls. We want this night
to be remembered for years to come.
- Hopefully.
- Come on, now.
- Okay. Okay.
- We know what to do.
Good.
Why do they look like that?
Come on, girls.
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"And the braids upon her back
are tinted with henna"
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"And the braids upon her back
are tinted with henna"
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"And the braids upon her back
are tinted with henna"
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"And the braids upon her back
are tinted with henna"
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"And the braids upon her back
are tinted with henna"
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"I am the daughter of a noble sheikh
Untouched by disgrace"
"The one with the finest qualities
is here, all the beauty lies within her"
"I am the daughter of a noble sheikh
Untouched by disgrace"
Wonderful, wonderful!
Did you see that woman
dancing alone in the middle?
Her dance was way off beat.
Did you see the statue they had?
Yes, it freaked me out.
I felt as if it was staring at me.
May God protect us.
That's how rich people are.
They like to get creative in their parties.
Candles everywhere,
a gloomy atmosphere...
Even their clothing is different.
Don't tell me you didn't feel it.
Shams, I don't feel good.
What's wrong?
I feel dizzy.
The place is so suffocating.
God protect you, Noura, what's wrong?
Lie down here and rest
until we prepare the next song. Come on.
Come, God protect you.
Say God's name, come.
Come on.
Excuse me, is there an empty room
where Noura can rest?
Upstairs, on the second floor.
The second floor.
Come, I'll take you.
No, stay here and prepare
with the girls. I'll go alone.
- But you don't look good.
- I'm fine. It's okay.
Noura, be careful.
I don't know. Should I keep going,
or just go back?
I apologize. I was only looking
for a room where I can rest.
I seek refuge in God
from the accursed devil.
In the name of God, the Most Merciful.
Kid, where are you going?
What's wrong with this earring?
It keeps falling off.
Shams, I'm going to run to the bathroom
before Noura comes back.
Don't be long, we'll start soon.
Take me with you,
I don't know the way.
Come on.
Where are you?
Come here.
Come over here.
Come, let's go down together.
Come on.
Open the door, kid.
Open the door.
Open the door, kid. It's dark in here.
Come, I'll go down with you.
Open the door.
God guide you, Noura. I'm worried,
and the guests are waiting.
May God guide you back.