Noura!
Noura?
Noura, is that you?
Noura.
Noura!
Shams!
I seek refuge in the Lord of humankind,
the Sovereign of humankind
the God of humankind,
from the evil of the lurking whisperer.
Who whispers into the hearts of humankind,
from among the djinn and humankind.
I seek refuge in the Lord of humankind,
the Sovereign of humankind
the God of humankind,
from the evil of the lurking whisperer.
Who whispers into
the hearts of humankind
from among the djinn and
humankind.
The Sovereign of humankind,
the God of humankind.
What do you want from me?
Sing for him.
If you don't sing for him,
he won't let you leave.
Sing.
"God will protect.
May you not return, nor be safe"
"God will protect me. May it never
return, may it never find peace."
"He passes by with his sword drawn,
AlArabs!"
"My beloved placed me in his heart"
"We're united..."
No!
Is something wrong?
No, I'm just looking for the restroom.
The restroom is this way.
- Shams, what's wrong?
- My dear!
- Look at her, Noura.
- What happened?
What happened? Talk to me.
What's wrong?
- What's wrong? Talk to me.
- Noura.
Look at me. What's going on?
What happened?
Noura, help me.
Tell us what happened!
The guests were asking about you
so I went upstairs to look for you.
I heard your voice on the second floor,
so I went up to find you.
But the walls covered in eyes, Noura.
All human eyes!
Then I heard a woman crying
in the next room.
But when I opened the door,
there was no one. No one, Noura!
Suddenly a man came out of the wall!
A tall, terrifying man
emerged from the wall. I was terrified.
He came close to me
and didn't let me go
until I recited
the protective verses, Noura.
Noura, it seems Shams is imagining
things. Everything is fine.
- I sweat it was real! I swear!
- I know. I know.
- Noura...
- Calm down.
- Listen to me.
- There's something strange in this house.
Look at me!
I saw something even stranger.
Calm down. Let's think about
what to do now. Calm down.
Take it easy. Calm down.
Calm down. Let's figure out what to do.
- Noura...
- Calm down.
Umm Murjana says we're ready.
Please come.
We'll be there in ten minutes.
No, no, no...
I'm not going.
- I won't.
- Shams...
Shams, calm down.
- Calm down.
- I'm not going.
We have to go to the hall now.
If you want to see your kids again,
we have to sing.
- But I can't! I can't.
- Listen to what I'm saying.
They won't let us leave.
We have to sing.
Ladies, go get ready.
Shams and I will be right behind you.
God willing.
Go on, girls.
Shams, you're like a sister to me
and I love you so much.
I don't want them to hurt you,
so we have to sing, okay?
Alright, just let me
calm down a little.
- Let me calm down, please stay with me.
- Relax.
- Relax, I'm here. I won't leave you.
- Don't leave me alone.
I'm right here.
I couldn't even get out of the house.
Every time I tried to leave,
I found myself back inside again!
Okay. So what do you expect me to do?
I'm so terrified I can barely stand.
Shams... Shams!
All we have to do is keep singing
until dawn.
- I can't.
- Just be patient.
Just hold on until dawn.
I can't, I can barely stand.
I can't go on.
The band is ready
and the guests are waiting.
Is there a problem?
Shams was feeling a bit tired
and needed some rest.
Shams, would you like something to drink?
You're djinn.
I know you're djinn.
This is a djinn wedding,
and I want to get out of here.
Yes, we are djinn.
And you know what happens
when we get upset.
Shams!
Shams is gone, and she's not coming back.
Where did you take Shams?
What did you do to her?
No one is leaving this house.
Go to the hall and continue the party,
or you'll all share Shams's fate.
Where's Shams?
Shams!
We'll sing "Daughters of the Tribes."
Don't tell anyone about anything
you see here tonight.
"Dance and don't mind
the daughters of the tribes"
"You are the star of the night"
"Dance and don't mind
the daughters of the tribes"
"You are the star of the night
You're the lady of honor"
"Sway as you wish
And take pride in your beautiful braids"
"Don't mind the daughters of the tribes"
Sing well.
- This is a djinn wedding.
- "Dance and don't mind
- the daughters of the tribes"
- Sing well.
"Dance and don't mind
the daughters of the tribes"
"The daughters of the tribes"
- Sing well.
- "Dance and don't mind"
- "Dance with your braids"
- Sing well so we can get out of here.
"Dance with your braids"
"Sway as you wish
And take pride in your beautiful braids"
"And take pride in your beautiful braids"
"Dance"
"Sway as you wish
And take pride in your beautiful braids"
"And take pride in your beautiful braids"
"Dance and don't mind
the daughters of the tribes"
"Sway as you wish
And take pride in your beautiful braids"
"Dance and don't mind
the daughters of the tribes"
Allah...
Move now!
- Allahu akbar...
- Oh dear!
- Get me out of here.
- Come on.
Oh my God.
- Oh dear!
- Move it.
- Hayat! Hayat!
- Easy.
-ِ Are you upset?
- Hold on.
Move. Why did you stop?
- Come on.
- Are you okay?
There was...
a wedding.
That house has been abandoned
for years.
- Abandoned?
- What?
Abandoned?
Do you need anything?
Do you need help?
Be careful not to go inside.
We've heard many scary stories about it.
Hang Qurans around the place.
- Did something happen?
- No. Are you alright, sweetie?
Hang them on the walls in every room.
I'm Major Walid from
the Criminal Investigation Department.
May I speak with you for a moment?
- About what?
- About Shams.
Her family filed a missing person report.
She's been gone since yesterday.
And when we asked your band members,
they said you were the last to see her.
Alright, is it okay if we talk later?
My kids are at home
and I don't want them to know anything.
Fine. Come to the police station
after sunset.
If you don't, I'll have
to get a warrant for your arrest.
I'll be there.
Okay.
Where's Shams?
I don't know.
Everyone in your band said
you were the last one to see her.
When was the last time you saw her?
- On the wedding night.
- The wedding in the abandoned house?
We didn't know it was abandoned!
I got a call about a wedding,
and when we went and saw...
You mean you saw the house was
abandoned and still went in?
It was just curiosity.
Who called you about that wedding?
I don't know, maybe it was a prank.
We went and saw the house
was abandoned...
So you, your band, and Shams
all went together?
You and Shams went into a room,
and you came out without her.
Tell me what happened
between you and Shams in that house.
- You won't believe me.
- Speak.
Whatever you have to say,
I've heard stranger things. Talk.
Speak.
We went to a djinn wedding.
The djinn took Shams!
Listen, don't waste my time
or the prosecutor's time.
A woman is missing,
and you're the prime suspect.
Tell me what happened
between you and Shams in that house.
I swear to God I'm not lying!
We went to a jinn wedding.
The djinn took Shams!
It was a djinn wedding!
Stay here. I'll check the generator
and come back.
I swear I won't say anything.
I'll stay quiet.
I swear I won't talk.
Once Shams entered the house,
we couldn't get her out.
I told you, you wouldn't be able
to handle the story.
Thank you for your time.
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
Sorry.
Do you want my advice?
Forget what I told you.
And don't tell anyone about it.
Delete the recording.
Don't ever listen to it.
Welcome, how can I help you?
I'm here about Shams's disappearance.
The singer Noura is the prime suspect
in the case.
The case is still open
and has been handed to another unit.
May I ask why the charges
against Noura didn't stick?
Because we didn't find a body.
Without a body, we can't determine
the cause of death or the weapon.
And we can't link a killer to the crime
without a murder weapon.
- So you think it's murder?
- There's no other explanation.
If she were alive, we'd
know her whereabouts
or someone would have seen her.
And there's no evidence she left Kuwait
through any border crossing.
What did Noura say
to defend herself?
Djinn.
She said the djinn took Shams.
I actually spoke to her.
She told me the same thing.
But what do you think?
Our work doesn't rely on the supernatural,
we only rely on evidence.
But there is something strange
and unnatural about this case.
Which is?
I went to the house where Noura
and Shams were before she disappeared
looking for evidence.
When I entered, I felt a strange heat.
The heat inside that house was
unnaturally higher than the outside
even though the windows
were open and broken.
There was no explanation
for the rise in temperature.
And I saw something strange.
I saw hoofprints,
but the size wasn't normal.
They were much larger
than they should be.
And in one of the ground floor rooms,
I found animal bones.
Some were still fresh,
which means they were recent.
Marzouqa says bones are food for djinn,
according to the Hadith.
But I also saw stray dog tracks there,
so maybe the bones were from their hunting.
On the walls of the second floor
I found writings, talismans
strange pictures and statues.
I think some people took advantage
of the house being abandoned...
and turned it into something
like an art exhibit.
The house was completely empty.
Except for a picture I found upstairs
that looked like Shams.
Or maybe I just imagined
it looked like her, I don't know.
How do you explain what you saw?
I told you, we're men of law.
We follow evidence.
If we open the door to the supernatural,
it will never end.
A killer could blame his crime on djinn,
a thief could accuse djinn of stealing.
- The law doesn't rely on that.
- You're right.
- One last request, if I may.
- Go ahead.
Can I see the picture
you found in the house?
I kept a copy.
"Case number 483-B"
Here.
It looks like the description Noura gave.
Forget what I told you,
and don't listen to the recording.
"I woke up terrified
from the nightmare I had."
"I ran to the door."
"When I stepped into the hallway,
I felt someone watching me from the left."
"When I turned, it was the same woman
I saw in the nightmare!"
Who's there?
"Journalist Mishal Zayed Shreida
dies under mysterious circumstances."
Sing!
"I met a handsome dark‑skinned man"
"He signaled to me with his eyes"
"He spoke to me, and I answered"
"And I followed him"
"He said 'don't leave me.
Don't disappear'..."