Aoife.
Soul, is everything okay?
We've heard the Bloods are on the move.
Where are you?
We're east of Ozanne territory.
And Marcus' boy?
He's lost.
For now.
How many of you are there?
Eight left.
Eight Hunters won't last long out there.
The Bloods will come for you.
The Bloods don't scare me.
Not anymore.
Let them come.
Let him come.
I made it to Wolfhagen.
We have numbers here,
weapons and supplies.
We can help you.
Yes.
Let it end where it began.
We'll draw that coward out,
and he can find out what it feels like
to die far from home.
You don't think I'm powerful enough
to take him on.
I think you will be.
You're going to find him, aren't you?
I'm coming with you.
It'll be dangerous.
You shouldn't go on your own then.
Are you okay?
Where's Bjorn and the others?
Tied up in one of the sheds.
Are they alive?
Yes, of course.
What about the prisoners?
That boy whose Giving Day it was.
His grandfather was killed
trying to run away.
I thought maybe if I used my power,
I could turn into him.
Complete the ceremony somehow.
It was worth a shot.
I don't know
what we're doing here anymore.
Soul has separate orders for you.
He wants you to track Annalise.
Bring her back.
You can take one of the bikes.
Pick up the trail.
We're going to Wolfhagen.
Do you know where that is?
Bring Annalise there, quick as you can.
Where's Annalise?
Annalise!
You're wasting your breath.
She went with Ceelia.
How do you know?
I saw them leave.
And you didn't try and stop her?
You didn't wake me up?
I didn't wake you
because I knew you'd want to go after her.
And?
And in two days, you turn 17,
and we have seen what happens
to Blood Witches
who do not complete
their Giving Ceremonies, have we not?
Look.
She wanted to go. That's her business.
My business is still here with you.
Okay.
Then let's get this done.
What are we gonna do
when we see my dad?
I'm gonna talk to him.
I'm gonna try and bring him back
to the Fairborn Council.
By force, if I have to.
Do you think
you can do that all on your own?
I'm not on my own, am I?
I've got you.
What's on your mind?
You're gonna think it's stupid.
Try me.
Okay.
It just feels like
I'm losing something that,
I don't know,
might not even really be mine to lose.
Like, I'm holding on to something
that might not even be a thing.
- You're talking about Nathan.
- Yeah.
We'll see him again.
Well, you don't know that for sure.
No, I don't.
Well, I just always thought
in the end, it'd be me and him.
This is so stupid, isn't it?
No.
I was six foot by the age of 13.
Bigger and stronger than all the kids
and most of the teachers too.
I used to slouch down to talk to people,
skip lunch to avoid bulking up.
And I was certain...
certain...
that I was gonna spend
the rest of my life alone.
But there were men and women,
friends and lovers,
and with time...
I started to fit into my own skin.
Thinking about the people
that you love isn't stupid.
It isn't trivial. It isn't a distraction.
It's the whole thing.
It's the whole fucking point
of everything.
Okay.
Thanks.
I just can't believe she'd leave
without saying goodbye.
She has her path, and you have yours.
You both have to walk them.
What are you,
fucking Yoda now or something?
Who?
Oh.
Jesus Christ. Don't worry.
I miss being on the boat.
Less walking on the boat.
Less complaining too.
Do you wanna hear
my Lord of the Rings theory?
Sure.
Okay, so Lord of the Rings, right,
it's these movies about this little fella
who gets obsessed with a ring.
- Yeah, I know what Lord of the Rings is.
- You didn't know who Yoda was.
Just tell me your theory.
Like, well... well, the Fellowship, right?
Mm-hmm.
All the hobbits and the elf
and the dwarf and everyone,
they go on this big quest,
and they get into mad fights with orcs,
and they're having battles,
adventures and shit, yeah?
Yeah.
Well, the whole time
they're always saying, "Ahh!"
"Won't it be great when we finish
this journey, and everything's nice,"
"and there's no more orcs to fight?"
Right.
But it seems like fighting orcs
and going on adventures
is what they like to do.
Like, take away all that
and they're just no one, really.
Like, they don't really
wanna throw away the ring,
because once they've done that,
they've all gotta go home.
All the fun's over.
The happy ending ain't that happy.
Frodo don't get to hang out
with his mates anymore.
He's just sat around jerking off
in the shire
thinking about all the funny shit
Gimli used to do.
You know, actually,
I'm not sure I have seen this film.
I mean, you get my point, right?
Like, even if something seems bad
at the time,
maybe it wasn't.
Maybe the bad times
were actually the good times.
It's a good theory.
The guard...
Shit.
Their hearts have been taken.
- Get Alice.
- Nicky.
Get her.
A necromancer.
Open to rest,
my brother, bring us your spirit.
Bring us your spirit,
my brother, and bring it quickly.
Open to rest,
my brother, bring us your spirit.
Bring us your spirit,
my brother, and bring it quickly.
What have you done?
What was necessary.
Brother.
What did you hear in the darkness?
Screaming, crying.
Pain and fear.
That was you, brother.
What about after?
When the shadows came?
What did they say?
Wolfhagen.
Is this it?
Yeah.
Doesn't look like much.
That's the point.
How does it work then?
Think of it like a train station.
Just have to find our platform.
Aw, now we're talking.
Mmm.
Where do you think
Annalise and Ceelia are?
No way of knowing.
Just asking what you think.
I think there's no way of knowing.
You want one?
Gotta say though, I think...
Is this supposed to happen?
Yep.
Jesus.
So we can go anywhere in the world?
If it has a Cut, yeah.
The number there matches the number here.
Uh, there's Mercury, 11.
The tower we passed on the way in.
And look, here. The one for Paris.
Shall we go back to the bar
for a quick drink?
It's tempting.
What's that?
Hey, Nathan. Don't go out there.
I'm gonna take a look.
We are trying to help you.
Nathan, wait!
He wasn't attacking me.
It's Jessica.
She wants...
- She wants... She wants...
- What?
What? What? What is it?
She wants to hurt
Annalise.
Don't...
Don't go...
Go.
"Don't go"? Don't go where?
Wolf.
I...
I... I, uh,
I just wanted to do something good.
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Stop. Stop. Stop it.
Stop it! It's done. Okay?
It's done.
I killed him.
What was he trying to say?
He said Jessica wanted Annalise.
He said, "Annalise, don't go wolf."
She's in trouble.
Yeah, wolf.
- Maybe he was talking about your father.
- No.
He wasn't.
He was. He was called Beef.
And he was
my brother's friend's... brother's?
Yeah, and they didn't want him anymore,
so I swapped him for an old iPhone 8,
because I was getting a new one.
And my mom went absolutely mad
when I brought him home.
Aw, I taught him how to stand
on his two legs and eat grapes.
I didn't even know that rats liked grapes.
And then you exploded him?
- Yeah.
- RIP Beef.
RIP Beef.
- Uh, what are you doing?
- Get out of the car.
Ceelia.
- Do you speak French?
- Not enough to carjack someone.
No!
What the hell are you doing?
I don't regret anything.
Your car.
Let's go.
- That's stealing.
- Sorry. Sorry.
What?
Go. Pardon!
We're sorry!
This is incredible what's happening!
Okay, I feel really guilty.
If that's the worst thing you end up
doing today, then count yourself lucky.
Here.
Call your dad. Find out where he is.
I don't know if I can.
Just keep it neutral.
Find out where he is.
We need to refuel.
Make it quick.
Watch the road!
Fuel up. Five minutes.
Dad, it's me.
Annalise, where are you?
Are you... Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm on the road.
We need to talk.
Where are you?
Getting somewhere secure.
Is... Is Kieran with you?
Kieran, no. I'm with, uh...
I'm... by myself.
I need you to get to me right now.
It's not safe out there.
Yeah, I will. I'm coming.
Just tell me where you are.
It's a Fairborn stronghold
called Wolfhagen.
- We'll be there by this evening.
- Wolfhagen? What is...
Let's go!
Let's go, move it. I said let's go.
Ceelia told me
about this place. Wolfhagen.
It's where my father...
It's where the Peace Massacre happened.
She's walking into danger.
We have to go help her.
We don't have time, Nathan.
- It's right there.
- We have one day, okay?
So we're going to go to Mercury.
We're going to get your blood,
and we're going to save your life,
and that's final.
What if it's not worth saving?
It is to me.
Got it. Cheers.
Where's the Cut?
It's out there.
Fucking hell.
On three?
Hey, look at me.
You can do this, okay?
Sometimes the bad times
are the good times.
Remember?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
You stupid idiot.
Nice.
Please be right.
Oh, shit.
Oi!
Okay. All right.
We must be close now.
We'll be there by nightfall.
What is it?
Two Fairborns. Close.
Go.
When we get there,
will you let me speak to him first?
Before you, you know,
start punching people.
I don't know.
I think he'll listen to me.
I reckon I can reason with him.
Whatever happens, I'm still his daughter.
He's still my dad.
Oh, my God!
Come on!
- Oh, God!
- Oh, my God! Ceelia!
Annalise, drive! Go!
Fuck you, Robin Hood,
and your merry band of cunts.
No welcome party?
Speech is silver. Silence is golden.
Yeah.
In a house of gold,
the clocks are of lead.
Weren't you going to say hello?
So...
Where is he?
He didn't come.
Oh, now, that is a shame.
He needs that. He'll die without it.
But I was very clear
he was to be brought to me.
Let me take it to him.
Oh, Gabriel.
You're smitten.
Where has he gone to?
Wolfhagen.
Wolfhagen?
Not sure that's a place
anybody wants to be right now.
Far as I understand it,
there's rather a lot of trouble brewing.
The fires have started burning.
And when those fires start burning,
they must be fed.
Lest they go out.
Where is everyone?
Maeve.
Hey!
Please. Please. I didn't want to do it.
I... I said we should just punish her.
We were told.
We had no choice.
Soul, maybe we sh...
Get him here.
Just give me a minute, please.
Aoife.
Soul, is everything okay?
We've heard the Bloods are on the move.
Where are you?
- We're east of Ozanne territory.
- And Marcus' boy?
He's lost. For now.
- How many of you are there?
- Eight left.
Eight Hunters won't last long.
The Bloods will come for you.
Bloods don't scare me.
Not anymore. Let them come.
- Enough. Enough!
- Let him come.
We should get out of here.
Silence!
Such a shame.
He was so full of potential.
All lost now.
Give me the blood
and I can bring him back here.
Oh, my darling angel Gabriel.
So hard to say no to such perfection.
You must tell me.
Is it love?
No!
Wait.
Oh, that. Um, that's nothing.
I'll take that for you.
What was I...
You were going to bed, my dove.
You've come such a long way.
And you're so very tired.
Gabriel.
I so miss you when you're gone.
Will you promise to stay awhile?
That's my beautiful boy.
Hello, Nathan.
Dad.
Annalise.
What are you doing here?
- What do you mean? You told me to come.
- No!
No.
You shouldn't have come.
Dad?
He's here.
You shouldn't have come.