What are you doing here?
I got here too late.
Uncle.
Kieran, I'm afraid I have
some awful news about your father.
I was thinking.
My left hand is still weak,
and I know I've been dropping it.
We should work on that.
Nathan, your grandmother is dead.
She took her own life.
So how...
She brewed a potion.
A Scarlet Kiss.
You heal quickly, Nathan Byrne.
Don't forget that.
Nathan.
You are not your father.
You're a good boy.
Blood...
Fairborn...
Whatever.
Reutger Sillwood is dead.
My brother is dead.
My colleague in the Fairborn Council,
along with her husband
and a whole squad
of Fairborn hunters are dead.
Your grandmother is dead.
I put these deaths
at the feet of your father.
Well, you've got me
training to kill him, so...
That was Reutger's plan. There's a new
plan now. You're coming back with us.
He's not ready.
- He doesn't need to be.
- I wanna stay here. I wanna keep training.
I wanna fight him.
- Soul.
- It's been decided, Ceelia.
- Clean up here and head back.
- Soul, who's in charge?
We're determining that.
You going to Gran's funeral?
Nah, probably too busy
with your new friends.
I don't know if I said this to any of you,
but I love the uniforms.
It's like Hitler Youth does paintball.
It's brilliant.
Was Boohoo doing a run on sports jackets?
Can you shut the fuck up?
What the fuck?
Oh, my fucking God.
Keep driving. Go past.
Keep going. Go past them.
Keep driving.
What the fuck! It's Marcus.
Drive! Drive!
Hurry.
Shit! Shit!
Shit.
Fuck. It's him.
Go past them. Go!
Keep going. Keep going round.
Go, go!
Holy fuck.
Get out. Get out!
Get out!
It's him. Stay alert!
Shoot on sight!
It's him. He was here. Your dad!
Fuck!
Shh! Keep quiet.
- That was my dad, wasn't it?
- Yes.
I just thought...
...maybe he'd...
What?
He'd come up and give you a hug,
tell you he missed you?
It's not that kind of story, Nathan.
♪ Lift up the evening ♪
♪ Just for a while ♪
♪ Backwards, upside down and inside out ♪
♪ So hold on ♪
♪ Or we'll all fall down ♪
♪ Oh, heave the oceans too ♪
♪ Won't you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh! ♪
♪ I'll keep my ears on ♪
♪ I'll keep my eyes open ♪
♪ Oh-oh! ♪
♪ I'll keep my legs in sight and wait ♪
♪ Till we all fall down ♪
What are we actually doing here?
You're not supposed
to be doing this, are you?
I'm not going any further
until you tell me...
God!
You hear heartbeats, don't you?
I can see it in you.
You're a heart eater.
A taker of powers.
I'm not my father.
You know,
I remember the first time I met him.
They say you shouldn't let
your power define you, but, uh,
it's hard not to feel slightly inadequate
when you stand next to a man
that can rip the magic
out of a witch's heart
and take it as his own.
And all you can do is
grow weeds out of the ground.
Maybe you should speak
to a therapist about that
after you untie me from this fucking bed.
Whose blood is that?
"His own blood will kill the wolf."
The coming dark and the waning light.
The promise of pain and endless night.
What does that mean?
It's a spell.
For what?
It's called a Witch's Bottle.
It's dark magic. Forbidden.
Why is it forbidden?
Because of the terrible things it does.
And the terrible things
you must do to cast it.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
There we go.
We're done for now.
Wait! Where are you going?
What happens now?
When it's ready,
I'll be back to finish the spell.
How do you finish the spell?
You'll see.
Yeah, the fuck I will.
Hey.
You stay where you are.
Stay there now. Don't move.
Don't do anything stupid.
I said, don't move.
Annalise.
Nathan?
Nathan! Nathan!
He's fucking lost it.
Nathan.
Have you heard anything about Nathan?
What?
I just assumed
you'd have people looking for him.
I think it's best
you forget about that boy, Annalise.
Darling, it's been months.
Maybe he doesn't want to be found.
- Hey.
You coming?
Revision club.
All the cool kids are gonna be there.
- Really?
- No.
Just us.
It'll take your mind off things.
I'm looking for Nathan.
Don't come back here.
Get on with your life.
How do you think you did?
I don't know. Okay.
- What about you?
- Smashed it.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Weren't you predicted to do super average?
- Predictions can be wrong.
- Oh, can they?
Yeah. Like I predicted at the start
of the year that you wouldn't kiss me.
And now I feel like you might.
Wow.
You're very cocky.
Do you like it?
Not usually.
So, am I right?
Would you kiss me,
or are you still pining for you-know-who?
"Pining"?
Yeah.
It's loud here.
Do you wanna go somewhere else?
Wait a second.
Over there. Come on.
♪ Satan, Satan, Satan, Satan... ♪
Oh, sorry.
- ♪ Said dance ♪
- ♪ Let's go... ♪
- Ooh, ow.
- Are you okay?
Come on.
Right, hang on.
Here we go. Push!
How are you feeling?
A little nervous.
There's nothing to it.
What do you think my power's gonna be?
A mother who can control water.
A father who can grow plants.
Maybe you'll make pond weed.
Ha ha.
Whatever it is,
I know you're gonna use it
to do great things.
Come on. Hurry up. Get ready.
Yeah, yeah.
On the day of your 17th birthday,
I give you your first gift.
Second gift. Your third gift.
This was my father's. Then it was mine.
Now it's yours.
Your family's blood runs through you.
Take of it and become whole.
David!
What are you doing?
Make it stop!
Annalise.
We have guards now?
There's been another attack.
Several, actually.
Reutger Sillwood was killed.
Oh, my God.
You don't have to worry.
We're perfectly safe.
But if he can get to the head
of the Fairborn Council...
Hey, I promise.
I'm not gonna let anything bad happen.
You need to worry about getting
your strength back and nothing else.
Okay?
Come on. Let's get you cleaned up.
We're just next door if you need us.
I have to ask.
Have you felt any...
twinges?
"Twinges"?
Of your power.
Oh, um,
no.
No twinges.
Well, it will come.
When it's ready.
Good night, darling.
Make it stop!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Grow!
Holy fucking shit.
- What have you spilled?
- Uh...
- A cup of tea.
- Annalise.
I'm sorry.
Why we put cream carpets
in your room, I'll never know.
Sorry, buddy.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
What do you think my power's gonna be?
Whatever it is,
I know you're gonna use it
to do great things.
- David.
- Mm-hmm.
- David!
Make it stop!
Dr. McGarvey,
operating room nine, please.
Dr. McGarvey, operating room nine.
Annalise.
David, what do you remember
from the accident?
Nothing.
- David, I...
- We were driving and then...
Yeah, and then
you put your hand on my leg.
- I wasn't trying...
- For fuck's sake...
- Asking what you remember from the crash.
- Pain.
I remember pain.
Inside me. Like I was...
Like I was...
Coming apart?
- When did it stop?
- When we crashed.
When I blacked out.
I think it's best
you forget about that boy.
Maybe he doesn't want to be found.
Annalise.
- What are you doing in here?
- Sorry.
I'm going to the office.
Stay here and watch the family.
♪ I said, "I don't know how we do it" ♪
♪ And you said,
"Just think if we'd have been together" ♪
♪ "We'd be breaking up" ♪
♪ I said, "I'd want the synth
And, "What a thing to say" ♪
♪ Do you remember how we spent our days ♪
♪ At the end of my garden? ♪
♪ Summertime, rope swings ♪
♪ Say the things
That no one knew about us ♪
♪ Well, there's no one else
Who gets me quite like you ♪
♪ Sparks in the sky
Until we meet the sunrise ♪
♪ Then see the year come into bloom ♪
Well, here's a face
I haven't seen for some time.
Hey, Steve.
Hey, your dad's not here,
as far as I know.
Oh, that's okay. I actually
just wanted to come use the library.
Well, strictly speaking, I shouldn't.
We're on something of a lockdown.
Oh.
I suppose half an hour won't hurt.
Go on. I presume you remember where it is.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
Stay there now. Don't move.
Don't do anything stupid.
I said, don't move!
Annalise.
Stop!
Run.
Oh, God!
Shit.
That way. That way!
Fuck it!
Jesus fucking Christ.
I just killed someone.
- Annalise. Listen. Hey.
- Please.
Don't touch me.
I don't wanna hurt you.
You won't hurt me.
I'm a fucking monster.
You didn't mean to do it.
That's all that matters.
All right?
My dad told me you'd run away.
They had me training. Up north somewhere.
- Training for what?
- They wanted me to fight my father.
Are you joking?
- There was a prophecy.
- What?
That you would fight one of the
most powerful witches that's ever lived?
That's just about the stupidest thing
I've ever heard.
Training was going quite well, actually.
Well, it would have to have been.
Well, anyway.
Plan changed.
What is it?
Your dad said it's a forbidden spell.
That's all I know.
What has he done?
It's your Giving Day in a week.
If you don't get your blood, you'll die.
What are we gonna do?
It's a map.
What?
A witch called Mercury spoke to me
just before the Fairborn Council took me.
She said if I ever needed help,
I just had to ask for it.
And this map would guide me to her.
Who's Mercury?
Don't really know.
- And what does she want with you?
- I don't know that either.
How does the map work?
- You don't know.
- No.
Just... Just ask for help
and the map will guide you.
Help.
Help! Help! Help! Help!
- Oi!
- Help.
If you're just gonna sit there,
shouting like idiots,
you can piss off outside.
Sorry.
But there's no 186.
It should be here.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I've never met a... Blood Witch before.
What if they're...
What?
Like, what if they're...
You know.
Bad.
We're fucking bad.
♪ Give me all your money
Give me all your shit ♪
♪ I ain't playing games, man
Use your fucking name ♪
♪ Freddie creeping, don't know why
This a stickup ♪
♪ Now you die ♪
♪ Ain't no time to stay alive
Murder once, you feel alive ♪
Hi.
There was a map.
On my hand.
It led us here.
♪ Give me all your money
Give me all your shit ♪
♪ I ain't playing games, man
Use your fucking name ♪
♪ Freddie creeping, don't know why
This a stickup, now you die... ♪
Well, there it is.
I've been wondering
when you were going to show up.
Been expecting us?
Well, I've been expecting him,
which is to say, I was told
that a young witch would be
seeking me out
at a time of his own convenience.
No one said anything
about, um, whatever this is.
I'm Annalise.
Oh, good evening, Annalise.
I'm Gabriel.
I work for a witch called Mercury.
And Mercury has offered her assistance
to our gawping friend here.
He needs his family blood.
Well, she has samples
from all the witch families,
so shouldn't be a problem
getting you sorted.
Why does she have blood samples
from all the witch families?
Because, um, desperate witches
will pay handsomely for them.
Who is Mercury?
She's a witch who can get you things,
like a vial of blood, a rare gemstone...
All kind of powders.
And potions.
Can she change someone's power?
- Why do you ask?
- 'Cause I'm interested.
Is it related to the blood in your hair?
Anything is possible.
- Where is she?
- Far away.
First, we must get to Paris
and then travel on from there.
Paris, France?
Yes, dear. Paris, France.
Uh, now, I have a bathroom
and a single spare towel,
which you may both use,
so why don't you go and clean up
while I make preparations?
- Preparations?
- Yeah, for the journey.
- To Paris?
- Yes, to Paris.
Don't you wanna ask
why we're covered in blood?
No, I don't, actually.
When do we leave?
We? Okay, uh, darling,
um, I was told to bring one witch.
And Mercury is not the sort of person
you want to surprise
with unannounced guests.
I don't care
what kind of person Mercury is. Darling.
I'm not leaving.
Now, you can either stand there
in your knickers and get in a huff,
or you can let Mercury know to expect me.
Well, I'd better put some trousers on
then, hadn't I?
You don't speak very much.
That is going to work well for us.
The bathroom is that way.
There.
There, there.
Hup, hup, hup, hup!
You don't have to do this
if you don't want.
No, I'm... I'm coming.
We're going together.
Throw out your clothes,
so I can get them clean.
Come on. We don't have all night.
Uh...
- Do you wanna...
- Uh, you can go first.
Please don't fuck
in my bathroom.
I really don't like him.
Yeah, really.
So, what's your power then?
Cooking?
Cooking, ha.
Well, that's one way of looking at it,
I suppose.
An ignorant way.
No, I'm not a chef. I'm an alchemist.
Right, so you make potions.
Any bog witch
can make potions, dear.
My powers are
a little more complex than that.
Yeah, yeah,
I'm sure they're really complex.
- Expecting anyone?
- No.
You know, in all of the excitement
of hosting, I forgot to ask.
Who are you running from?
Fairborn Council.
Oh, just the Fairborn Council.
I tell you what. Why don't we skip dinner
and get right on our way?
Yeah, good idea.
Is there a back entrance
to this place?
Yeah, in a manner of speaking.
Where are they? Where are they?
- You looking for bullets?
- No, I'm looking for the...
Everybody stay where you are.
Wow.
- Your training really was going well.
- Told you.
Okay, I got them.
- What are these?
- Bite down on it when you jump out.
- Jump where?
- The window.
The window?
If you're going to repeat everything,
this is going to be a long evening.
- Well, where's mine?
- Oh, darling, I'm sorry. I only have two.
No, she comes with us.
If only it were possible,
but I'm simply out of orbs.
Fine. Then I stay.
Lay down your weapons!
And lie down on the floor!
Can you
believe these motherfuckers?
First, they destroy my apartment,
and now they want me to lay in the dirt.
Hey, there is shit on the floor, asshole.
Why don't you lie down?
Send out my daughter unharmed
and you'll be dealt with mercifully.
- Did he say daughter?
- Yeah.
- Get out.
- Wait.
Now. You need to get the fuck out, now.
Give me my orb.
- She's not giving you the orb.
- Give me my orb.
You have ten seconds to comply!
Ten...
- Give me my orb.
- Nine.
Eight, seven...
- Shit.
- Six.
- Five, four.
- This is unbelievable.
Three, two, one.
Annalise.
Annalise!
Stay right where you are.
Annalise. Annalise. No!
♪ I heard you want your country back ♪
♪ Shut the fuck up ♪
♪ Uh-uh, you can't have that ♪
♪ I heard you want your country back ♪
♪ Shut the fuck up ♪
♪ Well, shit, me too ♪
♪ You stole it right outta my hands
And pulled the rug right under my feet ♪
♪ I'm Nat Turner meets Nat King Cole ♪
♪ A well-dressed brother
With a revolution in my soul ♪
♪ We the people in the street
Got the gammons in retreat ♪
♪ And their blood boils over when we speak
So let it be heard ♪
♪ We ain't wasting a scrap when we eat ♪
♪ And when we comе for it
Then we're coming to keep ♪
♪ Well, shit, me too ♪
♪ I heard you want your country back ♪
♪ I heard you want your country back
Shut the fuck up ♪
♪ I heard you want your country back ♪
♪ I heard you want your country back
You can't have that ♪
♪ I heard you want your country back ♪
♪ Well, you can not have that! ♪