We came to you
because we had nowhere else to go.
What can he do?
He can cook and clean.
He's a good boy.
What can he do?
We think he will be an alchemist.
- I already have an alchemist.
- He will be an exceptional witch.
Every mother thinks this of their child.
How many of your clan
did the Fairborn kill?
All but five.
And where will you go now?
We'll try to reach
our nearest family in Russia.
Perhaps if
he were an exceptional witch...
...he would know the ingredients needed
to ease his father's pain.
Gabriel, you know this.
Silver root. Oakwood.
Moss and stone and...
Lamb's blood.
Yes, that would do it.
Marie and Luc, I will take your boy
on the uncertain promise
he may develop
into something worth possessing.
Our business here is concluded.
No, I don't want you to go.
It is the only way, Gabriel.
Do not forget us. Ever.
No, Momma...
We will come back for you one day.
Remember that you are really brave.
My son, be strong.
Pap.
I want my mom and dad.
Dear Gabriel.
You have no mother and father.
Those were not your parents.
They were just two people
you used to know.
Just two more faces in the dark.
Sometimes you will dream of names
and not remember why they were important.
Write them down, Gabriel.
If only to remind yourself
that something was taken from you.
Yes.
Come, you have chores.
Hello, Nathan.
He's here.
His own blood
will kill the Wolf.
Oh, shut the fuck up.
"His own blood
will kill the Wolf"?
Fuck you. It's bollocks. All of it.
This whole time, he's been trying
to get revenge. That's all.
You wanna please him.
The Hunters are in that house,
so go and fight them.
Stop worrying about bullshit prophecies
and leave me the fuck alone.
Fuck.
Dad.
He's here, Soul.
You need her power.
Dad, don't listen to her.
Your Hunters can't stop him.
I can't stop him.
How are you gonna stop him?
Ice? He's got that. Fire? He's got that.
He's got every power you have,
except for hers.
She can't wield it, but you can.
He'll come in here,
and he'll tear you apart.
He'll do it slowly.
And then he'll take your daughter's power,
and there'll be no one left
who can stand in his way.
He'll wipe out our kind
until there's nothing left.
But you can save everyone.
Soul, look at me.
You can have everything.
You just have to be strong now.
Oh, my God, you are fucking insane.
Do you even hear yourself?
Dad.
Look at me.
It's not too late.
You can still do the right thing.
This is the only right thing!
You need to take her power.
No, I know you're a good person.
I know you don't wanna do this.
- You have to act now!
- Dad.
There is no time.
The Wolf is at the door, Soul!
I'm sorry.
Shit.
Bloods!
I'll get her.
Now you won't forget me.
Nathan.
Death to Fairborns!
I can't remember the fucking...
A journey of a thousand miles
begins with a simple step.
To dare is to do.
Cowards die many times
before their deaths.
She changed the password.
Go back to bed, you don't want her
to find you talking to me.
I'll go home to my mother
when the journey is done
and return to my home as the prodigal son.
Subtle.
You have no idea how important this is.
Thank you.
There's a shortcut
back to the water tower.
The boy before me made it to run away.
But he never used it.
Where?
Under my bed.
Why haven't you used it?
I'm afraid.
You won't always be.
I can't take you with me.
I know.
Will you believe me
when I say I'll come back for you?
I don't know.
I promise.
You're not leaving me, are you, Gabriel?
Yes.
But you promised you'd stay awhile.
I can't.
And where will you go to?
I'm going to help a boy kill a wolf.
This place has seen so much death.
The voices of the victims
are still in the walls.
Their blood is still in the ground.
Then let us hear them.
Split up. Find their leader.
Annalise.
You know who I am?
It's over. Please.
Then let's talk.
Tell the Bloods they have their meeting.
Tell them to come to Wolfhagen.
Please.
I was told
you was an honorable man, Soul O'Brien.
Are you honorable?
We are here
to discuss a peaceful accord.
These are our terms.
All Blood Witches must cease
the practice of traditions
that contravene
the Assimilation Declaration.
All Blood Witches
must abide by Fairborn law.
All Blood Witches...
I must stop you there,
Council Leader.
You see,
I didn't come here representing the clan.
I came here representing my father.
My mother.
I came here representing
every Blood Witch that has lost their life
to the so-called Fairborn Council.
Every Blood Witch
whose land has been taken,
whose children have been murdered.
I came here seeking recompense
for the lives you've taken.
- And the powers you've stolen.
Stop!
You are not supposed to be here.
Why aren't you with Annalise?
Why aren't you with Gabriel?
It was a good time to make a bad decision.
It's the worst time
to make a bad decision.
Well, I'm here now.
Did you get your blood?
I remember the first time I met you.
So tiny and little.
I picked you up.
And you looked up at me
with your big eyes.
And then you shit yourself.
We have to stop him.
I was supposed to protect you.
We can fight him together.
Go and find your friend.
My mom and dad are in there.
What's your name, sweetheart?
What's your name?
Ceelia.
Don't be scared.
I'll protect you.
I thought I was hiding
from a monster in there.
What happened to the man who hid with me?
I would have done anything for him.
A scared man
that couldn't defend himself.
Who had to listen
to his people being torn apart,
while he cowered in the dark
with a little girl.
There was honor in what you did.
Honor doesn't win wars.
What does?
Monsters.
That's what you learned in there?
Well, do you know what I learned?
I learned I'm not afraid of monsters.
Well, here we are.
Two witches in a cellar.
Playing a little game of hide-and-seek.
A little game
of let's cut out your fucking heart
and feed it to your dad.
Just another day
in the whirlwind life of Annalise O'Brien.
I thought maybe
I could come in here as Nathan.
But, nah. I don't need to hide who I am.
Because I don't think you've ever used
your power on someone willingly.
When you really need to use your power,
and, princess,
you really need to use your power now,
I don't think you have it in you.
So here I am. No tricks, just honesty.
And I'm honestly going to kill you,
Annalise.
Slice you open, take out your heart.
And feed it to your father.
The Bloods think that
when your powers are passed on,
a small part of you lives on
inside the person that takes them.
I like that idea.
I like the idea of you being stuck inside
your father for years and years,
just watching as he tears down
everything and everyone you love.
But then maybe I am...
What was it you called me?
"Fucking insane."
- You should have kept running.
- You should have let us go.
You can't control it.
I don't want to hurt you.
It's just you and me here.
You can tell the truth.
That guard at the Council,
the Hunter at the ranch.
Think what we could do.
Just leave now.
You're a Fairborn, Annalise.
We could kill those savages upstairs.
You could fill the air with their blood.
I bet you can feel it, can't you?
I bet you can feel them
coming apart at your fingertips.
You can't control your gift,
but Soul could.
Please go.
No one has to get hurt.
This isn't that kind of story.
Do it.
Annalise.
- What are you doing here?
- You pushed me off a water tower.
Did you get my blood?
Yes.
See, I knew it would be okay.
Why did you kiss me?
'Cause I didn't know it would be okay.
Drink it.
It's not dawn yet. Come on.
Annalise is here somewhere.
Get back!
Come on! This way!
Come on!
No, no, no, no.
Gabriel.
You okay?
You're okay.
Oh, no.
Oh, no. Nathan.
It's all right. It's all right.
You didn't bring a spare one,
by any chance?
No.
Thought it was worth asking.
Come on.
You die today, Fairborn.
Listen.
No howling.
No snarling.
Your wolf is not coming to save you.
Annalise.
Hey.
It's okay.
We're here. We're here.
All right?
- Where's Ceelia?
- It's okay.
His own blood will kill the Wolf.
Ceelia.
Ceelia. Hey. Hey!
Hey.
It's okay. It's okay. Just hold on.
Where is he?
Hunting.
Just hang on.
Please. Please.
To the friends at our table,
enemies in the dark...
and the ones we love who hunt them.
We need to go.
Go where?
To get your family blood.
Jessica.
Jessica!
Now what?
I'm all out of family members.
Oh, so you're just
going to sit down and die?
I can stand up and die
if it makes you feel better.
Your dad's still out there.
But you're not giving up.
We should think about
what we're gonna say.
What do you mean?
I mean, how many people get to know
when they're gonna die?
Most people probably go without saying
any of the things they wanna say.
So we should.
We all say the things we wanna say
to each other.
Okay, you go first.
You go first.
- You're the one on the countdown.
- Low blow.
Okay, I'll go first.
This has been...
fucking horrific.
But also...
...you know, kind of...
The bad times were the good times.
Yeah.
I mean, I don't know what's gonna happen
or how much time we have left together.
I will think about... Oh!
I will think about you
every day for the rest of my life.
I love you.
Both.
Oh, fuck.
Well, what do you wanna say?
Don't really know.
- Beautiful.
- Aw, come on.
Let me
get that sewn on a pillow.
"Nathan Byrne. I don't really know."
Okay, okay.
I love you both too, all right?
It'd be a shit time to die.
You know what we should do?
Have a quiet night in.
Yeah?
Just get, like, a takeaway or something.
- Make a nice change.
- Yeah.
No magic gunfights or nothing.
Maybe just watch a bit of telly.
What do you reckon?
I don't know where my dad is.
Fucked if I ever know where that guy is.
So, it's just you and me.
The Ozannes said you had
to kill someone from your own blood
to make the Witch's Bottle.
Who was it?
My brother.
Must play on your mind.
Maybe not.
You killed my mom.
You killed my gran.
I ain't forgotten that.
Now I'm gonna kill you.
And your father.
All your bloodline. Root and branch.
You gonna freeze me?
No, no.
You're gonna be awake for this.
All right.
I'll find you!
Hello, Nathan.
If you're here to kill me,
just get it over with.
We don't need to talk first.
I don't need to kill you.
You're already dying.
Guess the prophecy isn't true then.
What, "His own blood will kill the Wolf?"
We'll see.
Soul...
He won't find us.
Not for the time being anyway.
You're not so scary up close.
I think that might be
a matter of perspective.
Why did you kill all those people?
Do you wish to avenge them?
Most people, when they know it's coming,
they behave in the same way.
They lose themselves to their fear.
I killed this man once.
A Fairborn Witch.
Part of a hunting party
sent to look for me.
When I came for him, he was calm.
Eyes closed like he knew something.
Man died with a smile on his face.
And I got his heart and found his power.
He knew how he was gonna die.
That was his power.
There are many that would swap
all the riches in the world for that.
If he knew how he was gonna die,
why didn't he try and avoid it?
He knew that we all have
our time on this earth
and our part to play.
That was Mom's husband.
Yes.
- So, I went to her.
- Why?
Because I couldn't
stop thinking about the look on his face.
How he died like a man
that had known life.
She was nothing but good.
Nothing but light.
And I met her,
and I loved her, and she loved me.
Can you believe that?
It was everything.
And then they found us.
And I ran thinking that
they would leave her alone,
thinking they would leave you alone.
Well, they fucking didn't, did they?
No. I was wrong.
So you have that gift now.
You know how you die.
Yes, I know how I die.
And?
And it's not today.
Is the prophecy true?
It's your birthday.
You need your gifts.
And your blood.
My first gift to you
is your life.
I'm allowing you to have it.
Though many think I shouldn't.
My second gift...
is the last thing your mother said to me.
She told me that she wasn't afraid
of who you'd become.
She wasn't concerned with
whether you'd be more her side
or my side
or what people would think of you.
She said, "I love him, Marcus."
"For the good and the bad,
I will love him like I love you."
"And I'll be here waiting
until you come back."
But you never came back.
No, I never did.
I need three gifts.
That man killed your mother.
And your grandmother.
So now he needs killing.
- He's too powerful.
- Yes, he's got power.
But his mind is weak.
He doesn't know who he really is.
So, my final gift to you is this.
The chance to see who you really are.
You got your blood.
Not all of it.
Where's your father?
Gone.
Gone?
Try not to take it personally.
I just don't think
you're that important to him.
He left his son here to die alone.
Let's find out.
His own blood will kill the Wolf!
Well, I have his blood in me.
You can't stop it.
It's my destiny!
Nathan.
They'll talk about you.
They'll know I put an end to it.
They'll know I had no choice.
No!
Nathan, run!
Dad.
His own blood...
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Who are you?
Someone who likes to help people.
I like to help people,
and you like to hurt people.
Can you fix my power?
No, dear.
But I can get you revenge...
on the ones who broke it.