We must stay really quiet.
It's time for your story to begin...
Are you ready, Gabriel?
This is what I thought
Paris would be like.
Little bars. Cool music.
This is what I was searching for.
All of this.
All of... you.
There aren't boys and bars in Montana?
- I'm from Michigan, and...
- Oh.
...not like this.
Come back to my apartment tonight.
And then don't leave. Stay.
Stay, like move in?
I don't like it when you go.
I don't like waking up on my own.
I've been on this planet for 29 years,
and I've known you
for four months of that.
So I've got some pretty solid data
to fall back on
when I say my life is not as good
when you're not around.
So, come back to mine and don't leave.
You just say whatever it is you want, huh?
I don't say what I want.
I say what I need.
And if you can tell me
a better way to be happy,
I'm all ears.
Okay.
I'll get us some more drinks.
Hello.
Fuck!
Jesus Christ. Now?
She wants you.
- How did you get in here?
- She gave me a key.
I've had a long night, okay?
Can you just tell her
you couldn't find me?
Tell her yourself.
I need some Night's Breath.
Do you have any?
Try dumping them
instead of wiping their memory for once.
Hello, Gabriel.
You haven't been checking in.
I've been busy.
I have a job for you in England.
What kind of job?
Nothing dangerous, darling.
Just meeting someone.
Meeting who?
Hmm.
What the fu...
Annalise?
Oh, God.
What the fuck! Are you good?
Yeah.
Okay, let's go.
The Fairborn Council.
No one said anything to me
about the Fairborn Council.
I'm sorry.
They certainly didn't say anything about
the daughter of a Fairborn Council Hunter.
You need to go home
before you get me killed.
Shit! Where's my lighter?
She's not going anywhere.
Fine. Before we go any further though,
for the sake of trans-fucking-parency,
is there anything else
I should know about you?
- No more secrets.
- None.
We're going to need supplies.
As much vodka as I can get for that.
Hmm.
- What is your girlfriend doing?
- Um.
We're not really...
Well, I... I mean,
I... I don't think we're...
Oh, please, for the love of God,
finish a sentence.
We're not really boyfriend and girlfriend.
I don't know what we are.
Okay, that wasn't
worth the wait.
And a lighter, please.
There you go.
It's a peace offering.
An ugly plastic lighter
for almost getting me killed.
- How incredibly generous.
- If you don't want it, don't have it.
I didn't say I didn't want it.
I said I wasn't grateful.
Come on.
This is gonna be a long journey.
Yeah.
I may have lost my temper earlier.
I apologize.
There were several items of value
within that flat that I cherish dearly,
and now I shall miss.
- It's okay. I'm sorry that...
- One gold cigarette lighter.
One silk chiffon scarf.
A selection of vintage
Russian pornographic novels.
An embossed ebony walking cane.
- One antique...
- We're sorry.
Really.
Gold.
Vintage.
Gone.
To Miss Adventure.
That fickle bitch.
May she help us on our way.
Okay, what now?
We wait.
Are there a lot of Blood Witches
in Europe?
Thousands.
And the fains don't know?
You'll find that fains are incredibly good
at not seeing what they don't want to see.
Didn't you have
anything brighter or slower?
Gabriel!
Welcome aboard!
Long time.
Where is my goddamn money?
Oh!
You're very untrusting, Habir.
It's an extremely unattractive quality.
So is not paying your debts.
Who are these two?
- Who are you?
- Well, I...
My name is Habir. This is my boat.
Habir's a pirate.
I'm Annalise. This is Nathan.
Hey.
Got anything to drink?
Nice.
♪ Obviously... ♪
♪ You made me see ♪
♪ Can't take this life for nothing... ♪
Hmm?
Take it.
The more relaxed you are,
the less likely it is
you'll accidentally turn me into soup.
A girl with blood in her hair
talks about changing her power.
One does make assumptions.
It was an accident.
- What did you do?
- She doesn't wanna talk about it.
Oh, she didn't want to talk about
who her father was.
She doesn't want
to talk about what her power is.
But you want me to risk my life for you?
It's Decimation.
The undoing.
Not many Fairborns have a power like that.
Lucky me.
You just have to learn how to control it.
I don't want to learn how to control it.
I want it gone.
It's the best I can do right now.
♪ You always seem here ♪
♪ So I don't care anymore ♪
♪ What you say, no way ♪
♪ I don't care anymore ♪
♪ Oh, you do need me ♪
♪ There's a drawer
In a room in our house ♪
♪ That's calling your name ♪
"Do you see
the brightest star?" she asked him.
"That is the star
that will guide us home."
"But I still feel afraid,"
said the little boy.
"That's okay," said the little girl.
"And when you feel afraid,
I will squeeze your hand."
"And we will be brave together."
What happened?
We got the boy back
to the council building, but he escaped.
- How?
- He had help.
- From who?
- The Bloods.
They killed a guard,
turned him inside out.
Then they took Annalise.
She's a hostage.
So, we're going hunting.
Is that France?
Where the wild witches roam.
What do I do once I get my blood?
I'm not a life coach, kid.
I'm just here to get you from A to B.
Look, let's just concentrate
on keeping you alive.
Worry about the future when it gets here.
If it gets here.
That's the spirit.
Safe travels!
Albie.
Hi, Gabriel.
One adult, two children.
Okay, this will cover the three of you.
What's with the necklace?
Here, if you enter
another witch's territory,
you must acknowledge your presence
and pay your way.
Or else they might, uh,
you know, try and kill you.
Et voilà.
It's just fishing shit.
Okay, it's magic shit.
Welcome to Paris.
Come on.
My apartment is just round here.
What, is that where the Cut is?
No, that's where a change of clothes is.
Please remember we're on a tight schedule.
How could I forget?
You bring it up every five minutes.
This way.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Fuck!
Aww, shit! Been robbed!
Oh, no, it's gone. It's fucking gone!
What's gone?
Something
that's very fucking precious.
- You're having a bad few days, huh?
- You think?
Look, I'm really sorry
about all this, but we need to go.
The Council could track us here.
Or your father could track us here,
you mean.
No, we can't go until I've got my stuff.
- We don't have time to help you.
- You're not listening to me.
I can't make the next Cut
without my equipment.
My equipment is gone.
You see where I'm going with this?
No equipment, no Mercury, no blood.
- How are we supposed to get it back?
- The door isn't damaged.
So, you know,
whoever got in had a key, maybe.
♪ Hey! Listen! ♪
♪ Get it! ♪
♪ Listen! Get it! ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Watch out for those walls
Impregnated with our voices ♪
♪ Foundations witnessed all our choices
Charged up with electric current ♪
♪ Insulated background
That hid every word we quoted ♪
♪ And it molded and unfolded
All those moments... ♪
Where's Ruby?
I don't know.
I haven't seen her for months.
She robbed me.
She took my equipment.
No, it's not possible.
Ruby would never do that.
She was a goddamn drug addict, okay?
She used to rob you.
I used to dare her to.
It was a very funny game we played.
Well, look who's back.
Nicky.
Hmm. Sit down and have a drink.
Who are your friends?
They're cargo
for Mercury, from the UK.
They're Blood Witches.
I didn't think
there were any Bloods left in the UK.
Two less now.
- Hugo!
- Hmm?
Pour some coffee.
We've got a victim of crime here.
Gabriel, I was beginning to think
I wouldn't see you again. What happened?
Ruby robbed me.
I always said I didn't trust her.
You literally never said that.
He's a terrible judge of character.
This will warm you up.
Oh, no. I'm okay.
To the friends at our table!
And our enemies in the dark.
And the ones we love who hunt them.
It's been crazy since you left.
What's going on?
Word came over
of some troubles from the UK.
- The Fairborns killed a load of Bloods.
- The Bloods killed a load of Fairborns.
Which is good. Obviously.
Well, whoever started it,
it was a spark.
Now, we hear the Fairborn Council
puts their embassies on high alert.
All over Europe.
Why?
They're looking for someone.
Aren't you worried that the fains
are gonna find out? Or the police?
Fains we can deal with, but the gendarmes.
One in ten is a Fairborn anyway.
Why stay if it's so dangerous?
You think we should leave our home
because the Fairborns made it dangerous?
That's what led them
to drive us here in the first place.
I'm done running.
You might be a refugee.
I don't want to be.
That's all very noble,
but it doesn't help me get my shit back.
Agh, if Ruby has stolen gear,
there's only one place
she's gonna take it.
- Oh, no, please God.
- Aha!
Don't make me go.
I can't bear the smell.
The smell of what?
SPECIAL SHOP
MAGIC OBJECTS - BOUGHT AND SOLD
Ah, Gabriel.
I thought you were in London.
Yeah, I'm back.
Has Ruby been here?
Ruby? No.
Monsieur and madam,
would you care to browse?
I sell everything
a pair of young witches could need.
Huh? Et voilà.
A love potion.
Not that either of you would need it. No.
How about this?
- A lot of magic in a lost instrument.
- Oh!
Hey. Ruby.
- I have no idea. How about this?
- Please give me...
Bathe with this once a week.
And your enemies
will suffer great misfortune.
Okay, okay.
She came to me about a month or so ago
with a box of stuff to sell.
She didn't say it was stolen.
- Where is it?
- One of my regulars bought it.
Who?
You really need it, huh?
Everything has a price. You know this.
I can give you
the daughter of a Fairborn Hunter.
The girl?
What am I gonna do
with a Fairborn Hunter's daughter?
- Sell her back to them.
- What, I'm a kidnapper now?
No one gets hurt.
She goes home, you get rich.
And I get what I want.
Wait here. Give me an hour.
I'll bring your stuff. No funny business.
No funny business?
- What's going on?
- We reached an arrangement.
What do we do now then?
Wait patiently.
I got you something.
You mean you stole me something.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Never did get you
a birthday present.
We'll get to Mercury,
then go anywhere you want.
Just the two of us.
Hey! Hey-o!
Do I need to throw
a bucket of water at you?
Now is not the time or place.
What, Paris?
Okay, it is the place,
but it's not the time.
Gabriel.
Where is it?
There's a book.
There's a little book that should be here.
She never gave me a book.
- You sure?
- Yes.
We good?
Deal's off.
This isn't what I need.
You can't.
You promised me the girl.
What?
- Forget the girl, okay?
- Too late. I already cashed in.
- Run.
- What?
- Your friend sold you out.
- Run!
They went that way.
Do you like that story, Gabriel?
Will you look after it for me?
In a minute, we're going to go outside.
I want you to stay very quiet
and very close to me.
But if I tell you to run,
then you do not stop.
Even if you see something awful.
Even if you see us in trouble.
Even if we call to you
and beg you to come back for us.
Do you understand, Gabriel?
You run and don't stop.
Yes.
Remember that you are very brave.
And that I love you very much.
We tested
that stuff you had on you.
Cocaine.
Amphetamines. Heroin.
You're in a lot of trouble.
Blood Witch.
So, I wasn't carrying any of that shit.
Maybe some amphetamines,
but I don't think so.
Hmm.
You're on our turf now, Gabriel.
Mercury can't help you here.
But you can help yourself.
We're looking
for your traveling companion.
The daughter of a Fairborn Hunter?
Come on, I was bullshitting.
You think I'd really travel with...
If you tell me where he is,
it could make what comes next
less painful for you.
Huh?
Not the choice
I would have made.
Hey, look, it's the cargo.
Shouldn't you two be long gone?
What's he done this time?
Where's Nathan?
Where's Annalise?
I don't know.
Just our luck
to find the one loyal pirate.
I'm not loyal to anyone.
I just don't like you.
Thank you.
What do you know about Europe, Jessica?
It's dangerous.
Uh, yes, it's extremely dangerous.
And we're gonna be going
into the very heart of it.
We're gonna have to fight for survival.
We're gonna have to be ruthless.
We won't all make it back.
But I think you will.
Because I think
you can be ruthless, Jessica,
just like the best of us.
Oh, fuck!
Find out where they are.
Don't let us down.
You don't have to do this.
You're just a child.
People always want to tell me what I am.
But the truth is...
I can be anything I want to be.
Interesting.
Jessica.
I remember when we found that girl.
Two years old and scared to death.
Well, she's not scared now.
No, she's not.
Paris.
Good girl.
It's time to go.
Where?
Nowhere very nice, I'm afraid.
Hi.
Hey.
We need him here.
We're taking him across town.
Not now you're not.
His lawyer's here.
Lawyer?
Ah, there he is.
What are the charges against him?
Assaulting a police officer.
Drug possession. Mm-hmm.
And what are the real charges?
You think we don't know what you're doing?
You think you're going to
take another one of us
to disappear in your cells? No.
Mnh-mnh.
Not today.
Do you have any idea
what you're getting involved in?
Who he's protecting?
None of you are going to leave here.
What's going on?
He's using his power!
Ah, hello, Gabriel.
I had this all under control, you know.
Of course you did.
Hey, Hugo, the keys.
I can't believe
I'm breaking witches out
for the second day in a row.
You wanna be careful.
You're gonna get yourself a reputation.
Oh, yeah,
what's that like, having a reputation?
Has its moments.
Shit.
- Go, go, go!
- Get in. Get in!
I passed my test,
like, a month ago,
and I'm already getting in car chases.
- Are they following us?
- Can't see anyone.
Take the next left.
- Thank you.
- We only did it because we needed you.
Can you take us to Mercury? Now.
I still need my stuff.
Oh, my God! It's gone.
No, it's not.
I was just looking
in the wrong place for it.
I'll be five minutes.
Fuck it. We're here.
We might as well get a drink.
Thank you.
Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh!
We're gonna keep that. Thank you.
- To the friends at our table.
- And our enemies in the dark.
To those that hunt them.
Ahem.
Uh, how long does it take him to make
the Cut once he's got his equipment?
Gabriel doesn't make the Cuts.
They were made long ago.
What?
The doorway to Mercury is
at the bar we met you at earlier.
We could have gone through this morning
instead of running all over Paris?
Yeah. Why?
What did Gabriel tell you?
You stole from me.
You left me in a bar.
You ran away, and you left me.
And then you just... with no word.
Give it back.
'Cause I asked you to move in with me.
Just say no.
Just say, "No, Clark.
I don't want that. I'm not ready."
How hard is that?
How hard is it to not ask the question?
You knew that wasn't my scene.
You knew that, but you asked it anyway
because that's what you wanted.
Oh, sorry, "needed."
You needed to cross my boundaries.
Well, fuck you. And give it back.
I wish you worried about losing me
like you worry about losing that book.
Why did you take it?
It was the only thing that
would make you come looking for me.
Added my name.
I don't know why I bothered.
One day, Gabriel,
you're gonna find the guts
to see something through to the end.
Wha... What are you doing?
Hi.
Sorry, can I help you?
No, I just got lost
looking for the bathroom.
They're down the hall.
Thank you.
Uh, no problem.
Hmm.
- Blue Steel. Didn't you think?
- I thought it was good.
Get what you needed?
Yeah, we can go.
What was it then, that was so valuable?
Oh, my God.
A children's book.
It's a first edition.
- Fuck you.
- You lied to us about the Cut.
I bent the truth.
- What's so important about the book?
- Someone important gave it to me.
Who?
I don't know. Can't remember.
We could have been safe
with Mercury hours ago.
But instead,
we've wasted a whole day here.
We're running from the Fairborn Council,
from the Hunters,
from a murderous heart-eating psychopath.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What murderous heart-eating psychopath?
You're the son of Marcus Edge.
Excuse me, you're fucking what?
I'm the son of Marcus Edge.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
And the Fairborns are after you because...
"His own blood will kill the wolf."
A prophecy.
I'm supposed to kill my father.
Well, that is just fucking great.
That is just...
What happened to no more secrets?
Hmm?
Marcus Edge?
I should never have taken this job.
- It's fine by us if you want to leave.
- Oh, I ought to.
If you want,
we can take them through to Mercury.
We're going back to the bar anyway.
Sounds good to me.
Take them if you want to risk it. I'm out.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a life to get back to.
I wish you all the best.
Au revoir!
Don't worry about him.
Let's get you two
where you need to go, hmm?
Mwah!
Let's go.
Come on.
♪ Love, child ♪
♪ Reach, rise... ♪
So where is it?
How about a drink? Jacques, cognac.
Sorry, I'm just gonna..
♪ Scar, clear, fire ♪
♪ Clean, right ♪
♪ Pure, kind, sun... ♪
Hugo guessed who you were.
Me? I didn't believe it.
The son of Marcus Edge.
Half Blood, half Fairborn.
Your father fights for us.
He unites us.
And one day, he will lead us.
"His own blood will kill the wolf."
Uh, I'm not looking to kill my father.
Well, what you're looking
to do doesn't come into it.
It's what you're destined for
that matters.
And what you're destined for
cannot come to pass.
Nathan!
♪ No touch, no loss, no hand, no sense ♪
Aww, terrible idea.
♪ No need... ♪
♪ No will, no speech ♪
- Good evening.
- They still here?
They already went through the Cut.
Guess I was too late.
It's the Cut!
The Cut!
♪ No dream, no sleep... ♪
Nathan!
Annalise!
It's Gabriel.
Terrible idea.
♪ No time, no here, no pain ♪
Nathan! Nathan! Nathan!
Nathan! Nathan!
Nathan! Nathan! Hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Are you okay? Yeah?
Come on. We have to get to the Cut.
- I'm sorry.
- Now!
♪ Love, now, here... ♪
Apology not fucking accepted!
♪ Now, here, now, here! ♪
♪ Now, here, now! ♪
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my God.
Ah, it's quite clear
you cannot manage without me.
I leave you for five minutes.
Look what happens.
Now I can never go back to that bar.
Which I loved.
Best jukebox in Paris.
And now we'll have to take
the long way to Mercury's.
You're coming with us now?
Well, the thing is,
I actually don't
get paid unless I deliver you myself.
We have five days.
Can you get us there in time?
It's a long
and treacherous route, full of peril.
Almost certainly ending up
with at least one of us dead.
So, we're going to need
a very big bottle of vodka
and some comfortable socks.
- We should probably leave straightaway.
- Yeah, no shit.
You shouldn't have lied to us.
And you should have told me
who you really were.
Why did you come back?
I thought I should see it through
to the end.
A decision I'm already regretting.
Okay, let's go.
You coming?
Yeah.