Nathan Byrne!
- This is the Fairborn Council!
- Nathan!
You are surrounded.
Come out with your hands up!
You are a Blood Witch, Nathan.
By the laws of this land,
you're not permitted
to live within British borders.
So, what you saying? Gonna kill him?
No.
My family's power line is visions.
My mother, she was a prophet
and a far more powerful witch than me.
She wrote something on her last night.
The same night you were born.
"His own blood will kill the wolf."
A prophecy.
So, no,
I'm not going to execute you, Nathan.
I'm going to train you
because I believe
you are destined to fight your father.
What if I say no?
This is ridiculous! You can't take him.
He's only 16. He belongs here with me.
It's okay, Gran. I'll be back. I promise.
Will you tell Annalise what's going on?
I think we can both agree it'd be best
for my daughter to be kept out of this.
Okay, good. Let's go.
Nathan secured.
They train us
to kill Blood Witches.
But you...
They want us to take you up north,
keep you safe.
And we will.
After this.
- Right, over here.
- Right, let's go.
We'll get your dad one day,
but this will do for now.
Come on then!
You'll do, eh?
♪ Do what I do, it's what I feel... ♪
Blood Witch.
♪ T-I-M-E-T-O-D-A-N-C-E in the city ♪
♪ T-I-M-E-T-O-D-A-N-C-E in the city... ♪
♪ Do what I do, it's what I feel ♪
♪ Up to the sun, it won't be long ♪
♪ And now it's time for you to run ♪
♪ Hey, sister, come on, kick the world ♪
♪ The world is yours, up to you, girl
Amen, it's time to dance ♪
♪ T-I-M-E-T-O-D-A-N-C-E in the city ♪
♪ Hey, brother, get up, check the beat ♪
♪ Do what I do, it's what I feel ♪
♪ Up to the sun, it won't be long ♪
♪ And now it's time for you to run ♪
♪ The world is yours, up to you, girl ♪
♪ It was so fun, you feel so strong ♪
♪ And now it's time for you to burn ♪
♪ Amen, it's time to dance ♪
So, is there like
a Wi-Fi password or something?
No.
Whoa.
That smells disgusting.
What we doing here really?
I'm going to train you
to fight your father.
I don't expect, if you ever meet him,
that my training will keep you alive
for long, but those are my orders,
so that's what I'm going to do,
and you're going to comply
because if you don't,
then you're just another Blood Witch
in a land that doesn't want you.
I'm not a Blood Witch.
Fuck you. I'm not.
Then what are you, Nathan?
I don't know.
Well, we're going to find out.
Where's my bedroom?
- Is this a joke?
- Cottage isn't big enough for both of us.
- No shit. Look at the fucking size of you.
- This isn't a holiday camp. Toughen up.
Never actually been to a holiday camp.
Well, you won't know what you're missing.
Throw your stuff in.
Training starts right away.
We've got ten months
till you get your powers.
Until then, you have your mind,
and you have your body,
and we can turn
both of those things into weapons.
I can already fight.
- How did you do earlier?
- Not fair. There was more of them than me.
So you can only win fair fights?
That's not gonna be much use to us.
No one can beat eight hunters
on their own.
No one has fought your father and lived.
Our purpose here is
to make the impossible possible.
Hey, if you can teach me to
kick the shit out of eight of you fuckers,
then I'm all ears.
Let's see how you get on
against one for now, yeah?
Hmm.
- You have terrible technique.
- Fuck!
Mind and body, Nathan Byrne.
Mind and body.
How's the training going?
Is Kieran looking after you?
Yes, he's been good to me.
The program's tough.
They work us very hard.
Yes, we do.
How are the other cadets treating you?
There's been some comments.
My association with Nathan and...
And Marcus.
Yes.
You can't help that.
No, but it hangs around my neck anyway.
Well, we all have our baggage.
Not like this.
I was one of the architects
of the peace talks.
You may have heard them referred to
by their more common title,
the Peace Massacre.
There were many who are skeptical about
meeting the Bloods to discuss a truce.
I thought we could do
something incredible.
I thought we could change the world.
But Marcus Edge had other ideas.
I didn't realize. I'm sorry.
Whatever good I do, whatever I achieve,
I'll always be the man
who invited the wolf into our home.
You're a cadet in the armed wing
of the Fairborn Council.
If the past hangs around your neck,
pull it off.
This is your time
to define who you really are.
Ho, Nuno!
The objective of combat training
is to improve our skills,
not cripple our partners.
Go again.
The shadow of the wolf
spreads over Europe.
You are the first line of defense
for the Fairborn community.
So, you need to know your enemy.
Blood Witches heal
ten times quicker than Fairborns.
We use standard nine-millimeter bullets,
infused with composite spell formula
to bypass
their natural remedial capabilities.
Hands up, whose core power is elixir?
Great. So, you might know better than me
what the fuck's in these things.
What I can tell you is
if you hit a Blood with one,
they will know about it.
They're not superhuman.
We've killed a lot of them,
and we'll kill a lot more.
Magic bullets.
No one calls them that.
Ow!
Fucking hell, man. Fucking hurt.
Right, there's a natural circuit,
a five-mile run
if you follow the path.
I'll be timing you.
Not very fast.
- Do it again.
- What?
Come on!
Nathan!
I don't know why
they don't leave you alone.
What if they're right though?
What if I'm a...
fucking Blood Witch?
Nathan. You might be a Blood Witch.
Or you might not be.
One thing you're not is your dad.
When your brother
was trying to provoke me, I...
I wanted to hurt him.
I wanted to really hurt him.
Yeah.
That... That's what being provoked means.
Look, have you ever been into town
on a Friday night?
Moments of blind rage
are not unique to Blood Witches.
They're not unique to your father,
and they're not unique to you.
Honestly, just stop
feeling sorry for yourself.
It is your least attractive quality.
You think I have attractive qualities?
Shut up.
Hello, Ms. Byrne.
- I'm looking for Nathan. He...
- He's gone, love.
Gone where?
That's not your concern.
But I... I am concerned...
You're a smart girl, Annalise.
Don't come back here.
Get on with your life.
Go.
Breathe.
Focus!
Focus.
Don't point the gun at me!
Fucking breathe, please!
Jessica, must do better.
You know, with a few more weeks
training, you might even hit the target.
Hope we don't
get sent out together before then.
I hit the target plenty of times.
We're meant to be the best of the best,
so plenty of times don't really cut it.
Did your stepdad not teach you
how to kill properly?
I never met him.
Ah, well, you were only little.
Probably just don't remember.
Maybe he tucked you into bed
before getting in with your mom.
Your power
is shape-shifting, right?
So why don't you try and shift into
someone who's not a fucking traitor?
Okay, screw you.
- Oh!
- What?
Do I look like a traitor now?
Stop it.
Oh, don't be ashamed.
I think you look great.
I mean your boyfriend must be thrilled.
Couldn't believe...
His luck.
Oh, yeah, he's definitely
punching above his weight.
Oh,
no wonder you seem so frustrated.
Stop it now.
The next time you're alone with him,
you're gonna have that thought in mind.
What if it's not really him?
What if he suddenly...
changes?
Jesus Christ.
You wanna talk about daddy issues?
I can give you daddy issues.
You are fucking sick.
There is something wrong with you.
Change back now.
Hmm.
I hit the target plenty of times.
And I'll hit it plenty more.
♪ She don't care about me, she for you ♪
♪ And then talk shit about me... ♪
It's open.
♪ She be pushing buttons ♪
♪ When you come
You don't ask and start defending... ♪
Hey, I just wanted to come and make sure
that you're, you know, doing all right.
I'm doing fine.
So the whole Hazel situation...
She was... She was pretty upset.
So?
So maybe you could try
and smooth things over,
you know, for the good of the team?
As you've seen, my door's unlocked.
She's welcome to come and apologize.
Look, I know Hazel can be a bit difficult.
- But that's part of working...
- Kieran.
Your dad is a respected member
of the Fairborn community.
Your uncle is
head of the Fairborn Council Task Force.
Your whole life has been one
of privilege and ease.
Jess, I worked hard to get in here.
You passed a bleep test to get in here.
I worked hard.
My dad's dead.
And my name will always be stained
by association with a monster.
If I let them,
people will use that to tear me down.
They've been doing it my entire life.
So, she can come and apologize,
and I might let it go.
I don't show weakness, Kieran.
Some of us weren't born that lucky.
All right, I... I just wanted
to come make sure that you were...
you were okay, but I'll leave you to it.
You don't have to go
just 'cause I snapped at you.
You can stay.
If you want.
♪ You don't listen to me, me, me ♪
♪ All you know is protecting
That little bitch, bitch ♪
♪ Starting now, let me say ♪
♪ If I see, see, see her
She better not talk to me, me, me ♪
I wanna call someone.
Who?
Annalise.
There's no phone reception here.
Why don't you draw yourself
a little picture?
- Give that back.
- No.
You know what?
Fuck you! Fuck your stew,
fuck this cottage, fuck training!
I want to go home.
Okay.
You can go home.
All you have to do is pick up this book.
Fuck! Fuck!
Clean up your mess.
You're running the track.
Run it again.
Run it... again.
You're Nathan Byrne.
I'm not supposed to talk to you,
but you seem all right...
considering.
You look just like him, you know.
Bjorn, what's going on?
We got a distress call
from a Council member in Wales.
We think it's Bloods.
Could be Marcus himself.
- Don't we have people stationed in Wales?
- We do.
Then why are we going?
Because our people went
to investigate
and now we can't get hold of 'em.
- Why don't we just call them?
- Into the truck.
Let's go!
- Let's go, we're moving now!
- All right!
Hold position
until further notice.
All right!
Go. Go quickly.
Positions now, mate.
Hold, hold, hold.
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Help! Help me!
Don't touch her.
God, Jesus.
Suffocation curses are fast-acting.
They'll still be close.
Wait!
Oh, fuck's sake.
Looks like we found the first team.
This is Team Leader requesting
backup units on site.
We're gonna need a cleanup team as well.
- What about the bodies?
- They'll torch the house.
Unless you think
you can explain ten corpses
and a woman without a mouth to the fains.
- Pick up anything?
- Hmm.
They went this way.
Annalise, on the day
of your 17th birthday,
I give you your first gift.
Thank you.
I give you your second gift.
I give you your third gift.
This was my father's.
Then it was mine.
Now it's yours.
If your brother asks,
tell him I got it off eBay.
Thank you. It's beautiful.
All right.
You ready?
And now,
your family's blood runs through you.
Take of it and become whole.
Well done!
- Well done. Well done.
- Thanks, Dad.
When it was my giving ceremony,
your father was so jealous
that, uh...
...he tried
to cut his own finger all by himself.
We've sent everyone we have
over there as backup.
How did they manage
to take out an entire squad?
A whole squad of hunters.
- I don't know.
- Was he with them?
Marcus?
It's unlikely.
I mean, it's not like she was one of the...
Not like she was one of the Ten.
It should be the 12.
He spent the last two decades
hunting down the ten that gave the order.
What do you think he's gonna do
when he finds out that
the two of us actually carried it out?
You're both safe.
Your identities will die with me.
Whenever the day comes.
Well, either way,
I doubt he was there.
Her heart was still in her chest,
for one thing.
I mean,
that's usually a pretty big giveaway.
Hey, um,
Dad, Mom wants us to cut the cake.
Oh. Yes, of course, love.
Beautiful ceremony, Annalise.
Soul, your daughter
really is quite charming.
What's the point?
I'm never gonna beat him in a fight.
What's the fucking point?
A month ago, you wouldn't
have been able to do that.
Imagine what
you'll be able to do next month.
Hey, Beef.
Giving Day today.
What do you think my power's gonna be?
Maybe I can make animals talk.
Speak. Speak.
Fine,
be like that.
Strong, quiet type.
I thought he might have written.
Being my birthday and all.
Wouldn't kill him, would it?
Just a little letter...
...just to say hello.
"I'm still alive."
Speak.
Okay. Yeah, you're not gonna do it.
See you later, pal.
♪ ...after dark, it's my point of view... ♪
Annalise, it's your turn.
♪ Always coming
And you'd never have a clue ♪
♪ I never look behind, all the time
I will wait forever... ♪
Oh! One!
Hey, I got you something.
It's a puppy.
Okay.
Hope he's still alive.
Right. You might've wanted to put
some air holes in here or something.
- Because you always...
- Always smash my phone.
You're on here.
Well, I wanted to make sure
you remembered me.
Thank you.
Really.
You know,
you really are strikingly beautiful.
That's a bowling pun.
Thank you.
You have very heavy balls.
It's also a bowling pun.
It's the best I could think of. Sorry.
- Just gonna...
- That was cringe.
That was fun. You are terrible at bowling.
Shut up! I've never done it without the...
Oh, my God, what are they called?
The sausages down the sides.
The gutter guards.
Okay, well we professional bowlers
like to call them sausages, but okay.
I was thinking about, you know,
what happened last time
we were in this car.
Yeah.
I remember.
It was fun.
We should do that again.
Yeah, it... it was nice.
But?
Uh...
I... I don't know. I...
I don't really know what I want right now.
It seemed like you did
when we were together.
Sorry.
David.
David. David!
What are you doing?
Make it stop!
The trail ends here.
Four teams. Close the square.
First team on Jessica.
Third team on Kieran.
Fourth with Flo. Second on me.
No one gets away.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Left, to the left!
I got here too late.
Annalise.
Oh, my head.
You were in a car accident.
Where's David?
He's down the hall.
He was pretty badly hurt.
Is he gonna be okay?
He's gonna be fine.
Do you remember what happened?
Make it stop!
Not really.
Well, the most important thing is
you're okay.
Sorry, have to go.
I'll be back later with some magazines
and those horrible chocolates you like.
See you later.
Sir, we got them.
Excellent. Good work.
I'm afraid we suffered some casualties.
One of the new recruits.
Not Jessica?
No, uh, Cadet Hazel Clark.
Okay, I'm gonna see Reutger now,
give her the good news in person.
Well done.
- Aoife.
- I came as soon as...
It's Marcus.
Where were the guards?
We found
a few bits of them in the garden.
There was an insurgency in Wales.
We sent most
of our local protection detail there.
You think it was a diversion?
If it was, it worked.
The last of the Ten.
Are we safe?
- Seven of her fingers are broken.
- What does that mean?
It means that's how long it took
before she gave us up.
- He knows about us. We have to run.
- I'm not running.
My power is illumination.
Yours is growing bloody plants.
If the head of the council wasn't safe,
what chance do we have?
We're not as... powerless as...
as you might think.
There are ways.
What ways?
No, it's... Yeah, sorry,
you should... you should go. It's...
It's not safe
for you here anymore.
One mistake and a life spent
looking over our shoulders.
We were just following orders.
Yeah, well, now they're following us.
"His own blood will kill the wolf."
The boy.
If Marcus knows about the prophecy now...
he'll be after him too.
What's going on?
Reutger Sillwood is dead.
It was your dad.
- So what are they doing here?
- Been ordered to provide extra protection.
There's a concern
that your father may believe
that you're a danger to him now.
He may come here looking for you.
- How's training going, sunshine?
- Fine. You wanna fucking fight?
Come on, mate.
Okay, happy to.
Right.
It reflects poorly on me
when you get beaten so easily.
Well, maybe
you should train me better then.
Do you think
my dad's really on his way here?
I have no idea what your father's doing.
Maybe he'll come to rescue me.
He wouldn't be coming to rescue you.
- You learned a new recipe.
- Hmm. Fill my time somehow.
Thought you filled your time
beating the crap out of me. Cutlery.
That's the days.
The nights I have nothing to do.
- Try sleeping.
- I don't sleep.
Why not?
Bad dreams.
Maybe you should, like,
listen to a whale song or something.
Thanks for the tip.
You said I look just like him.
What?
My dad.
You said that I look just like him.
So you must have seen him then.
I was 11.
My parents both worked
for the Fairborn Council.
They were called
to a very important meeting.
To discuss peace.
The massacre.
They were excited to bring me along.
Told me I was going to witness history.
Well, they weren't wrong.
It was an old house called Wolfhagen,
in Germany.
Neutral territory.
My mother carried me in.
She put me in a chair
at the back of the hall
and told me to be very quiet.
I remember him coming in.
The way he looked at everyone.
And smiled.
Then he turned.
He became the wolf.
And he killed every one of them.
What did you do?
I hid.
Because I was just a child.
And I was afraid.
What about now?
Are you still afraid?
What are your weaknesses?
Hmm?
You're tired. You're slow.
You're not concentrating.
What are my weaknesses?
Underestimating me.
Your father
can control rock and water.
He can change shape into other creatures.
He can increase his size and speed.
Survive most wounds. Control weather.
He can make potions.
He can manipulate the heat and the cold.
He can take the power
of any witch in the world.
It's his greatest gift
and his greatest weapon against us.
The more of us he kills,
the stronger he becomes.
I'm going to the office.
Stay here and watch the family.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Soul.
Hello, Rowan.
I've never understood a man
who can grow whatever he wants
with the touch of his finger
spending so long gardening.
Ah, it's the old ways, brother.
I heard about Reutger.
Terrible tragedy.
It was Marcus.
Yeah, yeah, big cross of blood.
Heart ripped out of the chest.
He certainly has his methods.
He's hunting you, isn't he?
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna fight.
You know,
I've always liked our family's power,
but even I can acknowledge
its relative ineffectiveness,
when it comes to a fight.
Especially against a man like Marcus Edge.
Do you remember a book our father had?
You found it one time
when we were playing in his study.
It had a leather cover
with a symbol on it.
I remember.
And I remember
he beat us both just for looking at it.
Yeah.
I kept it.
When he died.
I've still got it.
That old magic is dead, Soul.
It should stay dead.
I only wish I had a choice.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
What is it?
Nothing.
Quickest time yet. Do it again.