Without Scorann I will not
have enough support.
I'll see you don't get
the majority you need.
I will become Jarl and
lead the alliance.
- (SARCASTIC CHUCKLE)
- That is how it shall be.
I was born a warrior... and I'll die one.
Isn't it convenient that your brother
vanishes on the eve of the Gathering?
Convenient for who?
For anyone who wants
Rheda to lose the vote.
Rheda shall keep peace in the
Shieldlands. My vote goes to her.
He's dead.
What's wrong?
I'm better with a blade but
I can only make them.
You get to use one in battle.
Your people don't want justice.
They want to see strength.
Rheda just sentenced your wife to death.
- Yaarrgh!
- Arrhh!
- Arrrhhh!
Vlade was your man.
You're behind all this.
As Hrothgar's successor,
I, Rheda of Herot...
(SIGHS)
As Hrothgar's successor,
I, Rheda, Thane of Herot,
lay my claim to become Jarl of all
the Shieldlands before this Gathering.
- I...
- (SOLITARY APPLAUSE)
I was just...
You were perfect.
Varr! Where are you?
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
If I don't win this vote, Rate will
challenge me to single combat.
- You'll win the vote.
- We can't know that.
Rate.
You're still here?
You're free of your pledge to avenge
Bayen's death. The Skinshifter is dead.
But the man who forced
it to do his bidding still lives.
If I lose and I'm challenged,
my brother thinks I'll step aside.
Everybody does.
Even you.
I will never step aside.
I will be Jarl before
this day's done...
... or I will die.
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.addic7ed.com -
(HUM OF CONVERSATION)
Silence!
Rheda, Thane of Herot!
As Hrothgar's successor,
Rheda Thane of Herot lays her claim
to be Jarl of all the Shieldlands
before this Gathering.
The other Thanes must
speak their will and vote.
Red for 'aye', black for 'no'.
As Thane of Bregan,
I vote for my sister, Rheda of Herot.
(CHEERING)
Lagrathorn, Thane of the Banning.
You made a good wife
to Hrothgar, Rheda,
but you're not the leader
of men he was.
The Banning vote no.
(CROWD MURMURS)
Rate, Thane of the Varni.
First, I bring a message
from a dead Thane...
my brother Scorann.
If Beowulf is to serve
you as Herot's Reeve,
you have his vote.
Beowulf, will you serve
Rheda as her Reeve?
I will serve... Herot.
Then Scorann, Thane of the Wisdeth,
speaks in your favour.
- (CROWD ROARS)
- But as Thane of the Varni,
my view is this.
A Thane lies dead, my shieldsman was
murdered under her protection...
and the stench of Skinshifters still
lingers within these walls.
- She make us vulnerable...
- MAN: Aye!
... even with Beowulf at your side.
My vote is no.
Two for. Two against.
(SHOCKED GASPS)
Let him pass.
Roth of the Mere.
My people were massacred by
the Warig 20 summers ago.
You thought all of us were dead.
But some of us live.
Before he died, your husband
promised us iron weapons.
If you give us these,
Gorrik, Thane of Mere,
will vote for you today.
You will have your weapons.
However, they must
not be simply a gift,
- but a dowry.
- This was not agreed.
The choice is yours.
Your son, Slean, must take
Gorrik's daughter as a bride
and bind our people in blood or
you will not have his vote.
(CROWD MURMURS)
We thank Gorrik.
A marriage between my
son and his daughter
will make our alliance stronger.
VARR: Rheda, Thane of Herot,
the vote is yours.
You are Jarl of all the peoples
and tribes of the Shieldlands.
(CHEERING)
Yes.
I vow to lead and protect you...
in the name of our ancestors,
as was the will my husband.
(CHEERING)
So you think she has your
interests at heart now?
And you do?
Careful uncle...
or I may have to tell
my mother how your
man Vlade was behind
Scorann's death.
Then why haven't you already?
I will not be married off to
some girl from the Mere.
A Thane's daughter.
(DOOR SLAMS)
And I wouldn't ask you to do this...
if there were any other way.
- You didn't ask.
- Did I have a choice?
Whoever manipulated Koll to weaken
my position is still out there.
Everything hangs in
the balance, unless
the Mere get what
they've asked for.
If there's another way tell me.
Leave us.
Easy.
Beowulf is Reeve now.
Thank you...for
accepting the position.
I didn't do it for you.
I did it for Hrothgar.
Still.
You'll go to Mere, collect
my son's bride.
Bring her back safely.
And take Elvina with you.
What?
- Why?
- She knows their ways.
- And?
- And...
... you will forget her now.
I've seen you look at Elvina.
And her at you.
It's not the way she
looks at my son.
(CHATTING AND LAUGHTER)
You don't like it?
When my people can
eat like this so will I.
Take what you can while
you can, that's my philosophy.
You should have told me
of your plans with the Mere.
- I could have helped establish...
- (DOOR SLAMS)
Slean.
Come... join your mother and me.
You wanted to know
who the traitor here is.
I've found him.
A man who forced a Mudborn
to murder Herot's Reeve,
whose hirelings killed
Scorann of the Wisdeth.
A man who sits at your table,
eats your food, drinks your wine.
who thinks his deeds
will go unpunished.
He's wrong.
Gold found under the boards
in the Skinshifter's house.
Gold that carries the
mark not of Herot...
... but of the Varni.
Is this a joke?
You found out the
creature's dirty secret.
Blackmailed it into
doing your bidding.
We pay gold for your iron.
These coins could have
come from anywhere.
I helped save your life.
Rheda, you believe this?
Without my warriors
this new Jarl of yours is powerless.
Without the Varnis
you're just a sorry collection of
farmers, fishers and miners.
You need us!
You leave me no choice.
My first act as Jarl...
is to expel the Varni
from the Alliance.
Without honour, no
matter how powerful,
a man is no better than a Mudborn.
(CHUCKLES)
This is a joke.
Hm? A joke.
- No!
- You ordered Bayen's death.
- And my brother?
- For the good of all
whatever price need be paid.
- Your words.
- Beowulf.
Now is not the time.
- Next time...
- Next time we meet...
... it'll be as enemies.
You're going then?
I'm not a Thane's son.
I have no choice.
You saw what choice I have.
My mother wants to drive us apart.
That's why she's sending you.
Maybe she's right.
You'll be married to another
woman. We have no future.
- I won't let it happen.
- There are no happy endings.
Don't you understand that?
- What future have we ever had?
- I've never let that stand between us.
And yet here we are.
You may come to love this girl.
You're going with them?
- Is that a problem?
- Why would it be?
- You've greased them.
- This is some of my best work...
- for some girl's dowry.
- For Herot's future.
- You have a gift.
- If the dowry doesn't reach Mere,
the deal Gorrik made
with Rheda is void.
It's two days hard ride
east to Old Mere.
- Then?
- Beyond the marshes.
The Island of Dunes.
My parents were of the Mere.
Gorrik knew a way.
The Warig couldn't reach us.
That's how we survived.
What are they like, the Warig?
Ugly, stupid and brutal.
I know the kind.
I don't think I
introduced my daughter.
He's not man enough to be
my mother, let alone my father.
(CHUCKLES) We should leave.
I'm sick of hearing
stories and never
having the chance to live them.
You will, one day.
Yah!
Harh!
Did you see something?
It's nothing.
She has the subtlety
of a stalking troll.
Less.
Fetch her in to ride with
us or send her home.
Nah, I'll leave her out
there a bit longer.
You heard what she said.
I'm not man enough to be her mother.
But are you man enough
FOR her mother?
Maybe that's the real problem.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(NEIGHS)
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey!
No. Hey. Hey!
(FRUSTRATED GROAN)
(SOFT THUD)
Argh!
Uh! (GROANS AND COUGHS)
(MENACING GROWL)
(GROWL ECHOES)
The Warig.
Stay with the dowry!
- Don't be a fool.
- Go on!
Vishka trailed us.
We'll stay here.
Argh!
(MENACING GROWL)
Vishka!
Vishka.
We have to move.
- The Warig will be back...
- (SCREAMS IN PAIN)
... with friends.
- (MOANS IN PAIN)
- Come on, let's go.
I know a place nearby.
(MOANS IN PAIN)
Go on!
- I was about to ride out.
- As was I.
How Lagrathorn voted is
of no importance now.
What's done is done.
- Do you agree?
- Yes.
Yes, of course.
Then you should know
what I'm planning.
- Which is...?
- One law,
one custom, one people.
Common laws cut into pillars
and placed in every settlement
across the Shieldlands.
Each Thane will see that their
people adhere to it or answer to me.
Common laws decided by you?
I'll listen to what others
have to say, but yes.
The laws are decided
up on by each Thane
and then agreed by their own people.
That is our way.
We can't cling to the old ways
and forge a new future.
I'll serve to our alliance,
as I swore to,
but I'll be damned if I'll
have any part of this.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Rheda, they are not ready for this.
People are always afraid of change.
You always wanted to
be loved, Abrecan.
That's your failing.
That's why you could never be Jarl.
And you are? Because you
shared Hrothgar's bed?
You don't mean that.
No.
No, forgive me.
I can be blunt but it
comes only from love.
As Bregan's Thane I will
see your aws hold there.
Your advice is always welcome.
But the decisions must be...
will always be... mine.
Alone.
Of course.
Leaving, Uncle?
To take news of the
Gathering to my people.
What news?
You could tell them the Varni are
banished for your crimes.
That you're in my debt.
She'll not give you what you want...
to be Thane.
I can.
It's been too long, nephew,
since you visited us in Bregan.
Take Vishka inside.
We'll put the horses in the corral.
What the hell are you
doing in my house?
- Get out of here!
- Malek.
It's all right. It's all right.
- (MOANS IN PAIN)
- It's all right, Aaron.
- Who are you people?
- Beowulf, Reeve of Herot.
Herot's laws doesn't hold
here in the edge-lands.
- We can pay you for your trouble.
- Keep your coin... and your trouble.
The girl needs help.
- What do you need?
- Grease, if you have it,
and honey to pack the wound.
- Aaron.
- Quickly, she may lose her arm.
Don't do this! Not my arm!
- Vishka, put the knife down.
- It's my fighting arm!
Please.
Save the arm. Just
take out the arrow.
Get me that.
She should drink this. It's strong.
- (COUGHS AND SPLUTTERS)
- Bite.
Whatever she told you...
it's going to hurt like hell.
(MOANS IN PAIN)
(WHIMPERS AND SOBS)
This is a Warig arrow.
They don't attack without a reason.
You must have done something.
She entered their burial ground.
And you came here?
(DISTANT GROWLING)
(WARIG GRUNTS)
(SPEAKS WARIG LANGUAGE)
(ROARS WILDLY)
With or without the girl,
we have to keep moving.
We're putting these people in danger.
- (DISTANT NEIGHING)
- The horses!
(NEIGHING)
(SHOUTING)
- Arrgh!
- (SHRIEKS)
- Ughhh!
- Rarrh!
You may not care what
happens to my people...
but if Gorrik doesn't get those
weapons, what of your own?
Rheda's claim to be
Jarl will be hollow.
Rate's an enemy. There
will be bloodshed.
And for what... a foolish girl who
doesn't know her place?
Out there the Warig would cut us down
before we even got a hundred yards.
If you haven't the guts
for it I'll go alone.
We stay together.
- You have no sway over me.
- I have this.
The dowry is my responsibility
until we get to Mere.
Door.
We wouldn't be in this mess if she
hadn't desecrated the burial ground.
I'd have left my own
daughter out there if
it meant getting those
weapons to my people.
- I will not give up.
- (MOANS SOFTLY)
It's still there.
But it needs stitching.
Did you do this?
I used to do a bit of carving myself.
Fence pegs, mostly.
You're a destroyer... not a builder.
Come away from him now.
(SPEAKS WARIG LANGUAGE)
(ALL CONVERSE IN WARIG LANGUAGE)
There.
The Warig... they took the horses so
we couldn't leave, didn't they?
What can I do to help?
Find something you can
use in a close fight.
- Fence pegs?
- I worked a farm.
On your own?
You had a family.
In another life.
What's this?
Warig work.
From the burial ground, isn't it?
- I...
- Isn't it?
- Vishka?
- I didn't realise it was important
and then I was going
to tell you but...
We have to give it back.
Now.
Malek? No!
It's our only hope.
Malek. Malek!
- Malek, if I'd known she'd stolen it...
- You'd have still come here.
The girl was in your care.
Malek.
- Malek.
- No.
Kragen... their chief and his priest...
they want us to take it to 'em.
- Back up.
- No.
Look, they wanted it,
they got it. Now back up - now!
Malek, don't be a fool! The archers!
Here.
Please.
The people that took
it were strangers.
They didn't know any better.
We've always shown you respect.
We just want to go on
working our land in peace.
(GRUMBLES SOFTLY)
Thank you. Thank you.
- (SNARLS)
- Arh!
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(SNARLING)
Inside! Inside!
(SOBS)
(SOBS PITIFULLY)
Something's going on.
They're trying to frighten us.
Well, it's working.
Barricade the doors.
Get up and help.
Vishka, you did a stupid thing.
Is that supposed to
make me feel better?
I don't care how you feel.
These things that
happened are your fault.
And the only way to make them
better is to help us stay alive.
Fatherly advice.
(DRAWS BREATH SHARPLY)
- (DISTANT DRUMMING)
- (MOANS SOFTLY)
Do you hear that?
(DRUMMING CONTINUES)
(YELLING AND SNARLING)
(SHRIEKS)
- The boy!
- They're coming round the back.
Quickly, move.
Get the door.
(SCREAMS)
Leave her!
Look at them. It's her they want.
- Let them have her.
- No! (CRIES OUT)
- No! No!
- Arh!
My people must live.
- Uh!
- (ROARS)
- (CRIES OUT)
- I've got you.
(SNARLS ANGRILY)
(BOTH PANT WITH EXHAUSTION)
They're pulling back. Why?
Oh, no.
This isn't the end.
They won't stop now.
BRECA: What do we do?
- They are out there somewhere.
- (DISTANT DRUMMING)
They're going to kill us
all... aren't they?
We all know what they're after.
Her.
She's what they want.
I'm taking her back to
the burial ground.
No.
- What do you mean?
- I take her out of here.
Ride through them. Buy the rest of
you the time to get out of here.
Those drums are summoning more Warig.
I can't.
You don't understand.
Elvina, please, they'll kill me.
Vishka, if we stay
they'll kill us all.
It has to be your choice.
Get food and water, only
what you can carry,
enough to see you to
the next settlement.
Come on, Aaron.
You and Breca will have
to carry the dowry.
You head out of here as fast as you
can. Go east, away from the forest.
You don't stop, you don't look back.
I'll look after the girl.
And yourself.
We'll see you on the road to Mere.
Your family, what happened to them?
When they needed me, I...
... I wasn't there.
Vishka.
There won't be any arrows.
They want you alive.
If you're going to be a warrior,
this is what it's about.
- Should I...?
- Look.
Only their priests can enter.
Hold.
(SNARLS)
(SHOUTING IN WARIG LANGUAGE)
Two of us on one
horse... even on foot...
they'd catch up to us
in an hour or two.
Here. I know what
will slow them down.
- (SPEAKS IN WARIG LANGUAGE)
- This ends here.
(SPEAKS WARIG LANGUAGE)
(ROARS)
(MOANING AND GROWLING)
(GROWLS)
(WAILING)
The Island of Dunes.
Home of the Mere.
Good to see you again, friend.
(LAUGHS)
You're alive?
Is that going to be awkward?
Should it be?
No.
That's it.
Now all we have to do is
give Gorrik the dowry
and get Slean's bride
safely back to Herot.
What could possible go wrong.
(RUMBLING)
Have a little respect for
your elders and betters.
- Vlade?
- Abrecan wants to know
if you'll help him become
Jarl of the Shieldlands
in Rheda's place.
And the prize you are
here to take from us...
Mara... my firstborn.
She's burning up. What's
wrong with her?
- Sea fever.
- My father would rather it
was I who was sick.
No father would ever wish that.
The Warig believe that a gland
found in the sand wrym's neck
- can be used to fight the fever.
- We have to hunt the sand wrym.
You know when you're drunk
and the ground moves?
- What if you're not drunk?
- Sand wryms!
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.addic7ed.com -
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org