- There's no turning you, is there?
- No.
Then I'll take you as you are.
You, my friend, don't know who I am.
Never come back to
Herot. You're dead to me.
Play the part your
mother has set for you.
She'll not be expecting when
we take power from her.
Do you want to be Thane?
Tell my uncle I am done with him.
You have hid in the
shadows for too long.
If you want power, take it.
If I tell my mother the
truth, I'll lose her trust.
And with it, any chance of ever ruling.
But if Abrecan
attacks, Herot could fall.
I have a vision for
us... to be the greatest tribe.
Abrecan is going to attack Herot.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
I won't let anyone hurt you.
Ever again.
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -
Abrecan would never betray me.
I speak only the truth.
I heard him call for his
people to attack Herot.
He's building an army.
This man is a thief and a murderer.
I believe him.
Our enemy are the Warig. This
prophet Razzak, not my brother.
Ready my horse.
You come to me and tell
me that Abrecan is a traitor?
Well, I will ask him to his face.
Rheda, you can't!
Wait!
Beowulf has told your
mother of Abrecan's betrayal.
How does he know?
Does it matter? She's
about to ride to Bregan.
I have to go.
I have to tell her.
That it was you that made her believe
the Varni was Herot's enemy,
plotted with Abrecan to overthrow her?
No, she can't go.
If she doesn't come back...
you will be Thane.
Rheda, you can't go to Bregan.
If it's true and Abrecan is a traitor,
then you're riding straight
into the arms of your enemy.
You're speaking of my brother.
- Let me take your place.
- No.
At least take an
escort of Slean's Huskarla.
The men are needed here
should the Warig attack.
- Now step aside, both of you.
- Mother.
Prepare the people to fight our
real enemy, the Mudborn. Go!
Abrecan won't harm her.
Whatever he's done or he's
planning, he would never harm his sister.
Let's hope you're right.
I see a land.
A land where the Mudborn roam freely
amongst the broken stones and empty
halls that were once our homes.
Where we are no more than a memory.
Like the giants that
ruled here before us.
This is our future.
Unless we are strong.
Some doubted that I cared
for the people of Bregan.
My people doubted
me... their rightful Thane.
I was once taught that a
good man forgives those
with the courage to
admit they are at fault.
With the courage to
ask for that forgiveness.
I also taught you that a good
man should have the courage
to stand by what he believes.
Your plans to attack your
own sister offend me.
Thank you for teaching
me this last lesson.
That a good man and a good
leader are not the same.
Argh!
If the Shieldlands are to
remain, we must be strong!
And I must be Jarl!
Greetings, Skellen, Warfather
of the Wulfing.
I have a proposition for you
from Abrecan, Bregan's Thane.
Further to the one the
Wulfing boy delivered.
It's one you'll want to
hear rather than kill me.
Good work.
Your sister will
hear what you're planning.
I know. And she will come.
When she does, will you string
her up alongside Harken?
You were the one who said, "Be bold."
You spent time in Bregan.
How many warriors can they
field if Abrecan wages war?
No more than 50. But
they're no match for ours.
And the Huskarla
are training the people.
Every person who can lift a sword.
Apart from the smelters. They
don't appreciate being told what to do.
Maybe not by the Huskarla.
Leave them to to me.
If there is war, all our
people must be ready to fight.
Right! You are all here to learn
to fight like Huskarla.
You townspeople are going to
fight with us to protect Herot.
Lila, you're with me.
Everybody, grab
yourselves a weapon. Let's go!
What kind of favour is this?
Well, if you're right about Abrecan,
we're going to need all
the help we can get.
So the favour... teach
them to fight. Fight dirty.
Smelters!
Like you, they ignore authority.
That's why you're gonna teach them.
This is Breca.
Some of you know him.
Some of you are owed money by him.
He's here to share a
few things with you.
Wait. Beowulf...
Come on! Sweat,
blister, bleed if you have to!
It's not Herot or a
Thane you'll be fighting for
when those Mudborn break
through those walls.
When they're in here among us,
you'll be all that stands
between those you love and the Warig.
Stand strong together and we shall win!
Right, you heard him! Back to it.
Rargh!
Wood splinters.
It's no good to
you, not in a real fight.
Iron.
This is the perfect weapon.
And it won't just kill a
man, it'll bury him too.
Better.
- Bah!
- Don't tell me you're not tempted.
You strike first, you
live. You don't, you die.
See, I told
you. Let them come at you.
If you're running at
them, you're not thinking.
If you're not
thinking, bad things happen.
Yah!
Harder!
Gil, the troll is hungry!
I told you, you have to clear out.
We have to bring the troll back,
it should have been fed hours ago.
When we're done. They
could do with a break.
Clear out, now!
- Have you ever seen an angry troll?
- I'm looking at one.
- Gil!
- It needs its salt!
Back down.
Breca!
Argh!
He's dead.
You see?
It was only a matter of time
before the Mudborn killed somebody.
It's killed a human. It's
angry, it could kill again.
We have to hunt it down.
Gil, go with him.
You, get back in there.
Everybody back to your training.
I'll come.
All right.
Don't let him kill it.
Bring it back alive.
What are you doing?
Elvina's gone, I thought I would erm...
I'm being insensitive.
Of course...
you cared for her deeply.
I loved her.
It must have been hard for you,
to see her so happy...
with Beowulf.
But we must be
practical. Herot needs a Healer.
Never more than at this time, when
we have enemies on all sides.
You think you can replace her?
Replace her?
No, I just want to help.
I'm not seeking your
permission to do this,
but I'd rather it
was with your blessing.
All right. Just don't poison anyone.
Elvina.
Beowulf said...
Said what?
That you were dead.
I'm sorry, I...
Does Slean know you're alive?
Kela, whatever was between Slean
and me, it's in the past.
You've nothing to fear from me.
Perhaps you could help me?
- What are you making?
- It's for the treating of wounds.
- Is that wormwood?
- The healer in Mere used it.
Yes. And celladine?
Yes.
I'd like it if we could be friends.
Aren't we?
Of course.
What you're using won't seal the wound,
but this will numb the pain.
Beowulf said the Warig killed you.
I escaped through the forest.
Kela.
You're telling me to leave?
Please.
Beowulf knows the truth.
What truth?
He knows what I am.
You told him?
He saw. I had no choice, it
was that or let him die.
A skinshifter saved his
life. He must have choked on that.
I won't let him harm you.
I won't.
Sister, this is an unexpected pleasure.
It has been too long since
you have been home.
I'm not here for pleasure.
I've been hearing things.
About Bregan.
About you.
Rumours.
Why does the body of one of
Bregan's most loyal and wise councillors
hang at the city walls?
- Rheda.
- Saray.
You must be tired after your journey.
Let me take you to wash.
Thank you, Saray, but I
need to speak with my brother.
Leave us.
Of course.
Run.
Maybe Kendra has a point.
The troll does the work of 20
men... men who could be preparing to fight.
We could take it back alive.
It killed a man.
The Mudborn have no place among us.
I only asked.
Like you said, it killed
because it was hungry, frightened.
We know the reason it
acted the way it did.
No! They don't reason. They just hate.
That's why the Warig
killed the Huskarla in the forest,
that's why the troll killed today.
Even if that were true,
where does hating them back get us?
With a little sense, to the point where
we find every one of
them and cut their throats.
Right, Beowulf, you understand.
Mudborn scum have
killed people I care about.
There are two sets of tracks
here. Gil, take Vishka.
Boy! Bring us some more firewood.
Firewood is hard to come
by here at the coast.
So your gift of the
pillar was most welcome.
Those laws were meant to unite us.
So they will... in warmth.
You forget yourself.
Not only am I your
sister, I am also your Jarl.
Oh, yes, so you are.
For today.
And who will be Jarl tomorrow, you?
If you're going to end
my life, do it now.
I never wanted to harm you.
Things would have gone a
lot easier for me if I had.
A ship leaves for the
Farlands on the next tide.
Give me what I want
and you will sail with it.
Refuse...
Beowulf, no!
Look, it's calmer. Let's take it back.
It doesn't belong
here. Please don't kill it.
Beowulf, he's gonna kill it!
Hey! Yaaaaargh!
- What's that?
- A decree.
Stating you relinquish your claim
to be both Jarl of the
Shieldlands and Thane of Herot.
Huh.
Even if I sign,
you need the other Thanes to
vote for you at a Gathering.
You threw Rate out. And
the others I can deal with.
And what is your
answer? Will you sign it?
I would never do that to my son.
Of course, your son.
Even without knowing
it, you prove I'm right
that you are the wrong
choice to lead us.
Because I care for my family?
Because you let your
heart rule your head.
Your son, your wonderful, loyal son,
he was the one who laid the
false blame on the Varni,
even though he knew it was
I who moved against you.
You're lying. Slean would never do that.
Just as he'd never have told my
men not to light the warning pyre
to alert Herot of the Wulfing raid?
You have no idea, do you?
You have absolutely no idea
what it's like to be related to you.
Sign, or I will do what must be done.
Thank you for bringing it back alive.
Thank Vishka.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm not gonna let you hurt her.
- Stay out of this, Slean.
- You think I don't know?
How long have you
known she was a skinshifter?
Years. It's never
made a difference to me.
We need to talk. The three of us.
You knew she was a skinshifter? You
put everyone in Herot at risk.
- She's no threat.
- I saw what she did to the Warig.
Which she did to save your life.
I'm a healer. I help
people, I don't harm them.
You think they'll care?
You saw what they did to
the skinshifter they found here.
They'll just drag you out
into the street and finish you.
- I won't let them.
- You won't have a choice.
Thane's son or not. It was an
open secret that she was your woman.
She's a skinshifter, she
can take care of herself.
But you... they'll have your life.
That's the law, that's what they
do to those who lie with the Mudborn.
Who's gonna tell them? You?
You do that and I will make
sure you are cut down with us.
Why did you come back?
Because this is my home.
You, as much as
anyone, know what that means.
Stay if you wish.
But this is on you.
Rheda would die before
she yields, you know that.
She has your strength.
You said you would stand by me.
This is not standing by me!
I have given her her chance.
A sister's blood will not wash away.
Then I will wear it with honour.
As I will have spilt it for my people.
We must prepare for what is coming.
You're burning up. Your wound...
You saved me from my darkness.
I will not stand by and let
that same darkness take you.
Let your sister go.
If you love me,
if you ever loved me, let her go.
You are nothing. A body
to warm my bed with.
Abrecan?
What's he doing here? I
thought you sent him away.
Well?
Their flags unfurl and
their sails catch the wind.
They will be here before nightfall.
They agreed to your terms.
You have done well.
Who will be here by nightfall?
What have you done?
Leave.
Now.
If I require your
services, I will send for you.
As you will.
Bring me my sister!
Leave us.
I've considered
everything you've had to say.
That is your answer, then.
It is.
I won't enjoy this.
What happened to you? What had to.
Argh!
I am glad you put up a fight.
He's alive. We don't have long.
Follow me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- You go.
- What about you?
- I'll follow.
- If they catch you...
Saray, he is beyond saving.
But you're not and Herot needs you.
- Over there! Stop her!
- Go!
Yaaah!
She got away.
It doesn't matter.
Soon, 200 Wulfing
warriors will be ashore.
You've allied yourself to the Wulfing?
They'll plunder Herot and then
sail back across the Whale Road.
They won't just plunder, they'll kill.
A few lives, some gold.
A small price to pay compared
to what they'll get in return.
A leader who can save the Shieldlands.
I should have taken your
life the night we met.
And to think I almost left with you.
I came this close to missing
what fate has in store to me.
See that her body is
burned with the other traitors.
After that, there will be
time enough or me to rest...
in Herot's Golden Hall.
Once the Wulfing dogs
have landed on our shores.
Stop.
My brother has betrayed
us. All because of my son.
He has allied Bregan with the Wulfings.
And now an army marches on Herot.
At the Draca Bridge,
with a dozen Huskarla,
we might be able to hold
them off for at least a day.
This could be Herot's only chance.
You must send word to the Varni.
I banished them from the Alliance.
Any messenger I send to Rate will
be sent back to us in pieces.
For glory!
Slean has gone
to stop the Wulfings.
He and his Huskarla will buy
you the time for help to reach us.
And he will not come back alive.
But he will die with honour.
Charge!
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org